Thanks dude.
ありがとう、相棒。
Last stage.
最後のステージ。
Last clicks. mãe a
ラストクリック。マエア
e
それは
d
d
m
メートル
e
それは
Good night to many of my colleagues
多くの同僚の皆さん、おやすみなさい
It is my pleasure to be here today to host our feast of knowledge today
今日は知識の饗宴を主催するためにここに来られて光栄です
Then you can see it from here
そしたらここから見れるよ
Today we are led by researcher Xu Yaru
今日は研究者のXu Yaru氏が指導します
Tell us about the Modai earthquake and tsunami
モダイ地震と津波について教えてください
I think we may have to wait a while to explain this topic
このトピックについて説明するにはしばらくお待ちいただく必要があると思います
Then let me introduce our keynote speaker today
それでは、本日の基調講演者をご紹介させていただきます
Dr Koh graduated from the Department of Earth Sciences, National Central University in 1997
コー博士は、1997 年に国立中央大学地球科学部を卒業しました。
is a very young and brilliant scientist
彼はとても若くて優秀な科学者です
After he finished his Ph.D.
彼が博士号を取得した後、
Once worked as a postdoctoral researcher at the California Institute of Technology
かつてはカリフォルニア工科大学で博士研究員として働いていた
Returned to Academia Sinica 11 years ago in 2006
11年前の2006年に中央研究院に戻った
From assistant researcher to assistant researcher
研究員補から研究員補へ
The researcher just became a political researcher two years ago
その研究者は2年前に政治研究者になったばかりである
Wait a minute talks about his field of study
彼の研究分野について話すのはちょっと待ってください
Mainly use this global satellite island navigation system
主にこの全地球衛星島航法システムを使用します
This is the GPS on everyone's phone
これはみんなの携帯電話の GPS です
use this signal to observe the entire surface of the earth
この信号を使用して地球の表面全体を観察します
deformation of the crust
地殻の変形
And our research on geodynamics
そして地球力学に関する私たちの研究
So the results of these studies
したがって、これらの研究の結果は、
can tell us something about earthquakes
地震について何か教えてください
About the tsunami caused by the earthquake
地震による津波について
Mainly this is the last generation
主にこれが最後の世代です
This term will be explained later
この用語については後ほど説明します
Dr Xu's research
徐博士の研究
We will invite him to serve as the main award today
今日の主な賞として彼を招待します
yes he has had a lot of good results lately
はい、彼は最近たくさんの良い結果を残しています
In 2010, he was awarded the Young Scholar Research Writing Award of the Academy
2010 年に、アカデミーの若手研究者研究執筆賞を受賞しました。
This is a domestic research for young researchers
国内の若手研究者向け研究です
Most of them are compared with the one who just started
ほとんどの場合、始めたばかりの人と比較されます
either teaching or research
教えるか研究するか
It is just starting to say that young scholars are more outstanding works awards
若い学者のほうが優秀な業績賞をもらえるといわれ始めたばかり
In 2012, he won the Memorial Award of Mr. Wu Dayou from the Ministry of Science and Technology
2012年、科学技術部より呉大佑氏記念賞を受賞
This is also a special award especially for young researchers
これも特に若手研究者に与えられる特別賞です
In 2017, this year won the Wu Jianxiong Academic Foundation
2017年、呉建雄学術財団賞を受賞
Taiwan Outstanding Female Scientist Rookie Award
台湾優秀女性科学者新人賞
And this year there is also a Geological Society of the Republic of China
そして今年は中華民国地質学会の会員も加わりました。
Wang Hanzhuo Dissertation Award
王漢卓論文賞
This is all in the geological world and the earth science world
これは地質学の世界と地球科学の世界のすべてです
Most likely to be one of the late picks in the younger generation
若い世代の中では遅れて指名される可能性が最も高い
So we are very happy to have Dr. Xu today
今日は徐先生をお迎えできてとても嬉しいです
give us some introduction
何か紹介してください
He is at the Institute of Earth Sciences of the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
彼は中医病院の地球科学研究所に所属しています。
So for this earth science research
この地球科学の研究については
And the thing about earthquakes that we are all most interested in
そして私たち全員が最も関心を持っているのは地震についてです
We all know that earthquakes are
私たちは皆、地震が起こることを知っています。
It's something we can't avoid
それは避けられないことだ
often come across
よく遭遇する
but for this
しかし、これに関しては
If it happens, there will be great disaster or damage
そうなったら大きな災害や被害が起きる
So we hope to say that in this study
したがって、この研究で私たちは次のことを言いたいと思っています
be able to understand a little bit more about earthquakes
地震について少し理解できるようになりました
maybe one day
いつの日にか
We can be able to predict or at least
私たちは予測できるか、少なくとも
Some understanding of these can save them from harm
これらについてある程度理解すれば、危害から身を守ることができます
able to minimize
最小限に抑えることができる
So okay, I won't waste everyone's time anymore.
わかった、もうみんなの時間を無駄にはしないよ。
Then please give warm applause
それでは温かい拍手をお願いします
Welcome to our today's keynote speaker, Dr. Xu Yaru
本日の基調講演者、Xu Yaru 博士へようこそ
Thanks
ありがとう
First of all, I would like to thank Vice President Zhou for his introduction.
まず最初に、周副社長のご紹介に感謝いたします。
And thank you very much
そして、本当にありがとう
It's "The Wind and Rain of the Hat" who came to listen to my speech
私のスピーチを聞きに来た「帽子の風と雨」です
So today I'm going to target my past 10 years
そこで今日は私の過去10年間をターゲットにしてみます
Some research done in the screen generation to report to you
画面生成時に行われたいくつかの調査結果を報告します
I will report the main words
主な言葉をレポートします
The cause of this screen generation earthquake
このスクリーン発生地震の原因
and a mechanism by which it occurs
そしてそれが起こるメカニズム
and some of the associated hazards that it caused this tsunami
そしてそれがこの津波を引き起こした関連する危険のいくつか
Then how do we use some of the current observation methods
では、現在の観察方法をどのように使用すればよいのでしょうか。
To understand the area where this large earthquake may occur
この大地震が発生する可能性のある地域を把握するために
Then use some relevant references for follow-up disaster prevention and mitigation work
その後、フォローアップの防災・減災作業に関連する参考文献を使用します。
First of all, the first question I want to ask is
まず最初に聞きたいのは、
Why We Are Studying the Great Earthquake of the Screen Generation
なぜスクリーン世代の大震災を研究するのか
That's because the big earthquakes of the screen generation usually have a large scale
それは、スクリーン世代の大地震は通常、規模が大きいためです。
And the range of its rupture is quite large.
そしてその破壊範囲はかなり広い。
For example, in 2004, the scale of 9.2
たとえば、2004 年のスケールは 9.2 でした。
This earthquake off the coast of Sumadawa
今回の須磨沢沖地震
The earthquake itself has a different rupture length
地震自体の破壊長は異なります
over a thousand kilometers
千キロ以上
And then he himself because of his mistake
そして彼自身が自分の間違いのために
has grown above the seabed
海底より上に成長した
So he created a big tsunami
それで彼は大津波を引き起こした
This tsunami is in addition to
この津波に加えて、
tree surface beat Yaqi Province
樹皮ビート ヤキ省
caused a lot of casualties
多くの死傷者を出した
He spread thousands of miles away to Thailand
彼は何千マイルも離れたタイまで広がりました
also caused many casualties
多くの死傷者も出した
The earthquake killed a total of 250,000 people
地震により合計25万人が死亡
So this is full
それでこれはいっぱいです
this damage
このダメージ
It's actually quite impressive
実際にはかなり印象的です
In other words, it is 2011
つまり2011年です
This earthquake off the coast of Japan with a scale of 9.0
今回の日本沖地震はマグニチュード9.0。
What about the earthquake?
地震はどうですか？
Although the Japanese government has expected that
日本政府もそれを期待していたものの、
there will be such an earthquake
そんな地震が起こるだろう
But I didn't expect the scale of this earthquake
しかし、この地震の規模は予想していませんでした
much higher than they estimated
彼らの推定よりもはるかに高い
so you see
ご覧のように
In fact, in their coastal city
実際、彼らの沿岸都市では
There are already enough so-called tsunami walls
いわゆる津波壁はすでに十分あります
The height of this wall is about 7 meters to 8 meters
この壁の高さは約7メートルから8メートルです
But what about the unfortunate tsunami?
しかし、不幸な津波はどうなるのでしょうか？
Far above this tsunami wall
この津波の壁のはるか上に
The slope height that can be defended
防御できる斜面の高さ
and then slow down here
そしてここで減速してください
These many areas in Japan
日本の多くの地域
caused many casualties
多くの死傷者を出した
In addition to the damage of the tsunami itself
津波そのものの被害に加えて、
Also because of the earthquake
地震のせいもある
The nuclear disaster that caused this Fukushima
この福島を引き起こした原発事故
The Fukushima nuclear disaster actually caused some harm to the entire ecology
福島原発事故は実際に生態系全体に何らかの被害をもたらした
just the longer one
長い方だけ
long-term process
長期的なプロセス
There is a way to counteract such damage
このような被害を防ぐ方法があります
Japan because they are among the people for
日本は彼らの一員だから
Earthquake disaster prevention work has been done thoroughly
地震防災工事はしっかりと行われています
So although its seismic scale
したがって、地震規模はありますが、
is also close to 9
も9に近いです
But its casualties were probably only 16,000
しかし、その犠牲者はおそらくわずか16,000人であった
With this number of people, about 250,000 people were killed or injured in the earthquake
この人数で、地震による死傷者は約25万人に達する
In fact, although it is an unfortunate large
実は、残念ながら大きいのですが、
Earthquakes in addition to triggering these tsunamis
これらの津波を引き起こすだけでなく、地震も
It's actually caused by strong vibrations on the surface
実際には表面の強い振動によって引き起こされます
it will cause some landslides
土砂崩れを引き起こすだろう
This is the time of Wenchuan Earthquake
汶川地震の時です
these landslides
これらの地滑り
These villages under this mountain
この山の下の村々
also caused many casualties
多くの死傷者も出した
This is the 2016 Yumoto earthquake in Japan
これは2016年の湯本地震です
Some landslides near Aso volcano
阿蘇火山付近で地滑りが発生
If the landslide flow is said to block the river course
土砂崩れにより河川の流路が妨げられると思われる場合
Yanse Lake
ヤンセ湖
If Yanse Lake breaks its embankment
ヤンセ湖が堤防を決壊したら
In fact, it will also cause great harm to the downstream residents.
実際、下流の住民にも大きな被害を与えます。
In addition to the strong vibrations of the earthquake itself
地震そのものの強い揺れに加えて、
It will also cause some older buildings
一部の古い建物も発生する可能性があります
or the island tower of some poorly constructed building
または、建設が不十分な建物のアイランドタワー
For example, the island tower of the Weiguan Building in the 2016 Meinong Earthquake
たとえば、2016 年の美濃地震における威関ビルの島塔
Although these are land earthquakes
陸地地震ですが
But because of the big earthquake on the screen
でも画面上で大地震が起きたので
if it happened at the edge of the land
それが地の果てで起こったなら
all these possible disasters
起こり得るこれらすべての災害
Big earthquakes can happen on the screen
画面上で大地震が起こる可能性がある
The next thing we learned about the big earthquake on the screen
次にスクリーンで知った大地震のこと
possible harm
危害の可能性
We just want to understand it and study it
私たちはそれを理解して研究したいだけです
Then today I will tell you
それでは今日はお伝えします
Let me introduce you to this process
このプロセスをご紹介します
what about first
最初はどうですか
I will first introduce the plate theory
まずはプレート理論を紹介します
Because it is closely related to the screen strip
スクリーンストリップと密接に関係しているため
Then we introduce
それではご紹介します
One way the crust of the screen strip deforms
スクリーン ストリップの表面が一方的に変形する
Then how do we use modern or
それでは、モダンまたは
different methods of observation
さまざまな観察方法
To understand the deformation of the screen with the crust
クラストによる画面の変形を理解する
Then what
じゃあ何
How to inversely calculate from this observation of Dibao
ディバオのこの観察から逆に計算する方法
The Situation of Chinese Americans at the Fault Level
過失レベルでの中国系アメリカ人の状況
Then I will introduce
それでは紹介していきます
Two screen strips near Taiwan
台湾付近の 2 つのスクリーン ストリップ
They are the Ryukyu screen belt and the Mara screen belt
琉球スクリーン帯とマーラスクリーン帯です。
what next
次は何
Because most of the screen strips are in the sea
スクリーンストリップのほとんどが海にあるため
So we need to monitor other than on land
だから陸上以外でも監視する必要がある
In fact, we also need to monitor the deformation of the seabed
実際、海底の変形も監視する必要があります。
So I'm going to introduce you to the deformation of the seabed
そこで海底の変形についてご紹介します
Then we will have a little summary at the end
それでは最後にちょっとしたまとめをさせていただきます
what about first
最初はどうですか
Let us first introduce the plate theory
まずはプレート理論を紹介しましょう
Because the scientists actually warmed the
なぜなら科学者たちは実際に地球を温めたからだ。
what did they find
彼らは何を見つけましたか
On this eastern coastline of South America
南米のこの東の海岸線で
and
と
fly some of the west coast
西海岸の一部を飛行する
It seems that this protruding place and this concave place
この出っ張ったところとこの凹んだところはどうやら
These two can be pieced together if moved over
これら 2 つは移動すると結合できます
So what do you say?
それで、何と言いますか？
scientists are thinking
科学者たちは考えています
Hey, are these two continents very close?
ねえ、この 2 つの大陸はとても近くないですか?
Were they linked together in ancient times?
古代にはそれらはつながっていたのでしょうか？
As for the doctors, they started looking for a lot of geological evidence
医師たちは、多くの地質学的証拠を探し始めました。
to see the possibility
可能性を見るために
Well, first of all, they will take a look at this ancient creature.
さて、まず第一に、彼らはこの古代の生き物を観察します。
Discovered South America and Flying Facts
発見された南アメリカと空飛ぶ事実
They have the same species that had the same creatures in ancient times
彼らは古代に同じ生き物がいたのと同じ種を持っています
What if at that time
もしその時だったら
South America and Fei Zhongge's One Atlantic
南米と飛忠歌のワン・アトランティック
There is no way this species can spread
この種が蔓延する可能性はありません
So the first condition for their species to spread
したがって、彼らの種が拡散するための最初の条件は
That is, these two continents are connected by Piling
つまり、この二つの大陸は杭でつながっているのです。
So they based on the distribution of these ancient organisms in different five continents
そこで彼らは、異なる五大陸におけるこれらの古代生物の分布に基づいています。
Then try to piece together what dimension these continents were in in the past
次に、これらの大陸が過去にどの次元にあったかをつなぎ合わせてみてください。
What about the other words?
他の言葉はどうでしょうか？
There is also some evidence of paleoclimate
古気候の証拠もいくつかある
For example, the direction in which a glacier is moving
たとえば、氷河が移動する方向
or from these three-pentagonal directions
またはこれらの 3 つの五角形の方向から
Then go to the previous time 300 million years ago
そして前回の3億年前へ
In fact, the situation in the mainland is like this
実は本土の状況はこんな感じ
That is, the five continents are connected together in the world
つまり、世界では五大陸がつながっているのです。
But now they are a separate
しかし今ではそれらは別々になっています
So scientists started to understand
そこで科学者たちは理解し始めました
In fact, the plate itself is for drifting
実はプレート自体がドリフト用です
it is for exercise
それは運動のためです
The new land may be in the central and deep city
新天地は都心の奥地かもしれない
Mainly because there are some radioactive elements in the ground and below
主な理由は、地面や地下に放射性元素が存在するためです。
can provide some fun
楽しみを提供できる
So the new land may be in the central and deep city
ということは、新天地は都心の奥地にあるのかもしれない
Then move slowly to the sides
それからゆっくりと横に移動します
that's why
それが理由です
Just move to the side
ただ横に移動してください
The sun is cooling down at once
日差しが一気に涼しくなってきましたね
It increases in density after cooling
冷却すると密度が増加します
After the density increases, it will slowly sink
密度が上がった後、ゆっくりと沈みます
And then finally the screen is under the continental plate
そしてついにスクリーンは大陸プレートの下に
Well, this actually has the above when we boil water
さて、これは実際に水を沸騰させるときに上記のことを行います
If there is a paradise below
もし下に楽園があるなら
Then the water will move to both sides
すると水は両側に移動します
which is similar to
に似ています
In the process of cloaking the oceanic crust
海洋地殻を覆う過程で
friction with the upper plate
上部プレートとの摩擦
And then there's what's called an earthquake
そして、いわゆる地震が起こります
That's why there are many big earthquakes in the Era
だからこの時代には大地震が多いのです
that's why it happened
だからそれが起こった
If we look at the past over 4000 years
4000年以上の過去を見てみると
Distribution of Earthquakes in World History
世界史における地震の分布
You can see that red represents the number of casualties
赤が死傷者の数を表していることがわかります
More than 1000 people
1000人以上
Yellow is probably the number of casualties between 100 and 1000
黄色はおそらく死傷者数が 100 ～ 1000 人であることを意味します
Other colors are relatively minor earthquakes
他の色は比較的小さな地震です
You can see that the major earthquakes are around plate boundaries
大地震がプレート境界付近にあることがわかります。
For example, along the perimeter of the Pacific plate
たとえば、太平洋プレートの周縁に沿って
Then the South Park of Eurasia
それからユーラシアのサウスパーク
Near the Sanda Trench we just talked about
先ほどの三田海溝付近
In fact, there are quite a few earthquakes here.
実際、ここではかなりの数の地震が発生しています。
But because there are relatively few people living here
しかし、ここに住んでいる人は比較的少ないので、
So the casualties are not as heavy as in other places
だから犠牲者は他の場所ほど多くない
This is also the distribution of historical tsunamis
これも歴史上の津波の分布です
Probably also the distribution of historical tsunamis over the past 3600 years
おそらく過去 3600 年間にわたる歴史的な津波の分布も
There are many causes of tsunamis
津波の原因はいろいろある
it can be triggered by an earthquake
地震によって引き起こされる可能性があります
Can be erupted by underwater volcanoes
海底火山によって噴火する可能性がある
or caused by landslides under the sea
または海底の地滑りによって引き起こされる
If it is caused by an earthquake
地震が原因の場合
It is displayed here in a circle
ここに丸で表示されます
you can see that is to say
つまりそれはわかります
Most of these catastrophic tsunamis
これらの壊滅的な津波のほとんどは
In fact, they all revolve around the Pacific plate.
実際、それらはすべて太平洋プレートの周りを回っています。
nearby
近く
Circum-Pacific Seismic Belt
環太平洋地震帯
it's happening here
それはここで起こっています
After we learn about some of the behavior of screen strips
スクリーン ストリップの動作の一部について学習した後
Let's see if it's on screen
画面上に表示されるか見てみましょう
How did the crust of this place deform?
この場所の地殻はどのように変形したのでしょうか?
here is a
がここにあります
sorry
ごめん
ok , sorry , let ' s broadcast like this
わかりました、ごめんなさい、このようにブロードキャストしましょう
This picture depicts the deformation behavior of hidden tendrils
この図は隠れた蔓の変形挙動を示しています。
You can see that the oceanic crust is slowly creeping down
海洋の地殻がゆっくりと下がっているのがわかります
But because it is a fault because of the relationship between the underlying layer
でもそれは下層との関係による故障なので
moshaleh effect it belongs to the state of doing
モシャレ効果、それはやっている状態に属する
Then it can continue to move in a deeper place
その後、さらに深い場所に移動し続けることができます
The cryptic effect is going on all the time
クローキングの効果はずっと続く
So in places closer to the trench
したがって、溝に近い場所では
this is the place
ここが場所です
The entire continental crust will be arched
大陸地殻全体がアーチ型になる
You can see there is a reference station GPR station here
ここに基準局 GPR ステーションがあることがわかります。
inland direction movement
内陸方向への移動
until this station reaches the maximum displacement
このステーションが最大変位に達するまで
Energy accumulation has no way to accumulate more energy
エネルギーを蓄積しても、さらにエネルギーを蓄積する方法はありません
it produces earthquakes
それは地震を引き起こす
If the earthquake breaks out to sea it creates a tsunami
地震が海に波及すると津波が発生します
and caused a lot of casualties
そして多くの死傷者を出した
after the whole gag is over
ギャグが全部終わった後
Energy starts to accumulate again
エネルギーが再び蓄積され始める
Then start the cycle of the next earthquake
そして次の地震のサイクルが始まります
This is the lattice deformation of the screen strips we often see
これはよく見るスクリーンストリップの格子変形です
So in a place close to the sea structure
海の構造物に近い場所なので
It will be found that after the earthquake
地震後に分かること
Has some terrestrial imaging role
地上の画像処理の役割を果たしている
For example, this is a coconut tree by the sea
たとえば、これは海のそばのヤシの木です
Basically, these coconut trees should grow above the intermediary zone
基本的に、これらのヤシの木はゾーン間の上に成長する必要があります
But now they are all within the range of the interzone
しかし今ではそれらはすべてインターゾーンの範囲内にあります
and many coconut trees are dead
そして多くのヤシの木が枯れてしまいました
Mainly because of the coast caused by this earthquake
主に地震による海岸の影響
generate a large number of renders
大量のレンダリングを生成する
caused the death of these many coconut trees
これらの多くのヤシの木が枯れる原因となった
Here is also a case presented in the ground
こちらも現地で紹介された事例です
If we were to take a closer look
もっと詳しく見てみると
Screen deformation behavior with earthquakes
地震による画面の変形挙動
We can simplify slightly
少し簡略化できます
represented by the following diagrams
次の図で表されます
Suppose this line represents the surface
この線が表面を表すと仮定します
This line is the interface of the panel of the screen
この行は画面のパネルのインターフェースです
We can move faults across plate interfaces
プレートインターフェースを越えて障害を移動できる
represented by this diagram
この図で表される
We can see this line
この線が見えます
The above is called the top plate, and the bottom is called the bottom plate
上を天板、下を底板と呼びます
If this place can be
この場所ができれば
free screen words
無料のスクリーンワード
location across the fault
断層を越えた場所
a surface deformation you see
目に見える表面の変形
It's just a jiedihan tree
それはただのジディハンの木です
That is to say, everything east of this line belongs to ascending
つまり、この線より東側はすべて昇順に属します。
All west of this line are offline
この線より西側はすべてオフラインです
It's because of fault sneaking
それはフォルトスニークのせいです
it belongs to a locked state
ロック状態に属します
So we often observe
そこで私たちはよく観察します
The phenomenon is that the deformation is very small near the fault
現象は、断層付近の変形が非常に小さいということです。
But far from the fault
しかし、間違いからは程遠い
The magnitude of its movement is just like that of the original factory.
その動きの大きさはまさに工場そのもの。
That is, the plates move at the same speed.
つまり、プレートは同じ速度で移動します。
That's because earthquake observations can tell us
それは地震観測が教えてくれるからです
where the fault might be located
障害が発生している可能性がある場所
So what?
だから何？
we have this
私たちはこれを持っています
The observation data of this original factory
このオリジナル工場の観測データ
There are also some observational data based on faults
断層に基づく観測データもある
we can speculate
私たちは推測することができます
What should the Jianghai Earthquake look like?
江海地震はどうあるべきか?
Because what these two villages need is equal to this
この二つの村に必要なものはこれに等しいから
this cold tree
この冷たい木
Then we can speculate
それから私たちは推測することができます
What about the Jianghai earthquake?
江海地震はどうですか？
the extent to which it may break when it occurs
発生したときに壊れる可能性がある程度
Then its possible fault geometry
次に、その可能性のある断層の形状
what is it like
それはどんな感じですか
what if
仮に
Let's look at it another way
別の見方をしてみましょう
This is the deformation behavior of the surface
これはサーフェスの変形挙動です
Then if we look at the motion behavior on the fault
次に、断層上の動きの挙動を見ると、
can be represented by this diagram
この図で表すことができます
This representative is Fault Huayi
この代表者はフォルト・フアイです
The case of a distribution at different depths
異なる深さの分布の場合
You can imagine the energy slowly accumulating at a relatively deep place before an earthquake occurs
地震が起こる前に、比較的深いところにゆっくりとエネルギーが溜まっていると想像できます。
Because in a relatively deep place, because of the relationship between the delayed temperature and pressure characteristics
比較的深い場所にあるため、遅れた温度と圧力特性の関係から
it's some plastic deformation
それは塑性変形です
So the plate can always be on the screen
プレートを常に画面上に表示できるようにする
Then the energy slowly accumulates in the deep place
そしてそのエネルギーはゆっくりと深いところに溜まっていきます
If we assume that the line of earthquakes in this place is around 1000 years
この場所の地震列が約1000年だと仮定すると
Then this fault slips at a rate of 2mm per year
そして、この断層は年間2mmの速度でずれます。
Then you know that after 1000 years of sliding
そうすれば、1000年間滑り続けた後、あなたはそれを知るでしょう
It has actually accumulated 20 meters of this energy
このエネルギーは実際に20メートル蓄積されています
Then the process of accumulating energy is a very slow process
エネルギーを蓄積するプロセスは非常に遅いプロセスです
However, when an earthquake occurs, it is a very fast process.
しかし、地震が発生すると、その進行は非常に速いです。
Let's say it's been 1000 years
1000年経ったとしましょう
Then the upper fault has reached a zero connection
その後、上部の障害はゼロ接続に達しました
an earthquake rupture
地震の破裂
This earthquake rupture may take 20 to 30 seconds
この地震の破壊には 20 ～ 30 秒かかる可能性があります
Then the whole rupture is done
その後、全体の破断が完了します
so you can imagine
想像できるように
You have to accumulate energy for 1000 years and that's it
1000年分のエネルギーを貯めればそれで終わり
Released at 20 seconds and 30 seconds
20秒と30秒でリリース
the harm it caused
それが引き起こした害
Of course it is considerable
もちろん相当なものですよ
At this time, if its energy is fully released
このとき、そのエネルギーが完全に解放されると、
Then it will slide 20 meters
そうすると20メートル滑ります
Then if you slide 20 meters
それで20メートル滑ったら
this is if your family
これがあなたの家族なら
If I'm next to the fault line
もし私が断層線の隣にいるなら
I think it should be asexual
アセクシャルであってもいいと思う
will be greatly damaged by these
これらによって大きなダメージを受けることになる
if it doesn't fully suspect
完全に疑わない場合
For example, in some places it is just
たとえば、いくつかの場所では、
it doesn't release all the energy
すべてのエネルギーを解放するわけではありません
after the earthquake
地震の後
It will also have a persistent so-called post-earthquake doubt
いわゆる震災後の疑惑も根強く残るだろう
to release the energy
エネルギーを解放するために
Then this time scale may be
この時間スケールは次のようになります。
Timescales of years to decades
数年から数十年のタイムスケール
Then this is probably one
じゃあ、これはおそらくその1つです
One way the Earth's crust deforms
地球の地殻が変形する一因
Then let's see
それでは見てみましょう
Sumatra Screen Strip
スマトラ島のスクリーンストリップ
Since this place was in 2004
この場所は2004年にあったので、
This magnitude 9.2 earthquake occurred
このマグニチュード9.2の地震が発生しました
Then this green area
それからこの緑地
is the range where it breaks
壊れる範囲です
Then one degree is roughly equal to 110 kilometers
したがって、1 度は約 110 キロメートルに相当します
you see how far it breaks
どこまで壊れるかわかりますか
In fact it has been more than 10 degrees
実際には10度を超えています
So there's more than 1,000 kilometers of rupture
つまり、1,000キロメートル以上の断裂が存在するということだ
What about this hidden belt?
この隠しベルトはどうでしょうか？
In fact, it is the junction of the hard Austrian plate and the Shangda block
実際、それは硬いオーストリアプレートと上達ブロックの接合点です。
The aggregate number of that plate is about 57 mimi per year
そのプレートの総数は年間約57ミミです
Except for the magnitude 9.2 earthquake in 2004
2004 年のマグニチュード 9.2 の地震を除く
It actually had another earthquake with a magnitude of 8.7 after 2005
実際、2005 年以降にマグニチュード 8.7 の地震が再び発生しました。
Then follow up
その後フォローアップ
Earthquakes of magnitudes 7 and 8 also occurred in Sumida West Toilet
墨田西トイレでもマグニチュード7、8の地震が発生
Then you can see there are some
そうすれば、いくつかあることがわかります
For example, the magnitude 7.9 earthquake in 1881
たとえば、1881 年のマグニチュード 7.9 の地震
1797 and 1833
1797 年と 1833 年
those old earthquakes
それらの古い地震
how scientists know to say
科学者はどのようにして言うことを知っているのでしょうか
There was a self-written earthquake in that era
あの時代に自ら書いた地震があった
OK, let's make an introduction for you next.
さて、次は自己紹介をしましょう。
It is how we monitor the deformation process of these vertical shells
これは、これらの垂直シェルの変形プロセスを監視する方法です。
then we used various methods
それから私たちはさまざまな方法を使いました
A way to compare current observations is to
現在の観測結果を比較する方法は次のとおりです。
Global Navigation WeChat Positioning System
グローバル ナビゲーション WeChat 測位システム
Interferometry with Synthetic Aperture Radar
合成開口レーダーによる干渉法
This is all using WeChat technology
これはすべて WeChat テクノロジーを使用しています
Then what
じゃあ何
If you want to know the relatively old events
比較的古い出来事を知りたい場合
you have to rely on some examples
いくつかの例に頼る必要があります
For example, let's go pick some sea-grass
たとえば、海藻を採りに行こう
some nutrition for dating
デートのための栄養補給
or we go to see the coral reef
それともサンゴ礁に行きますか
an example of his growth
彼の成長の一例
Then I'll introduce you one by one
それでは1つずつご紹介していきますね
First of all, let's introduce
まずはご紹介します
GNSS
GNSS
What about this? In fact, he is a
これはどうですか? 実際、彼は
It is the same as our usual car navigation
通常のカーナビと同じです
It's just that the accuracy of car navigation is actually
ただ、カーナビの精度は実は
maybe a few meters
おそらく数メートル
But we do this scientific research
しかし、私たちはこの科学的研究を行っています
The precision of our medicine may be up to
私たちの医療の精度は、
The level of minimeter
ミニメーターのレベル
In fact, now this
実は今、これが
There are different countries in the sky
空には色々な国がある
different countries have satellites
さまざまな国が衛星を持っています
Then do the positioning
次に位置決めをします
Like the United States, there is this GPS system
アメリカと同じように、このGPSシステムがあります
In Russia, there is a Gonus system
ロシアにはゴヌス制度がある
Then in Japan they have the QVSS system
日本にはQVSSシステムがあります
Then EU has this potential rate system
EUにはこの潜在的な料金システムがあります
Then mainland China also has their Beidou system
中国本土にも北斗システムがある
What about these satellites?
これらの衛星はどうなるのでしょうか？
is probably
おそらく
The satellite orbits at an altitude of about 20,000 kilometers
衛星は高度約2万キロメートルを周回
Then its track design is different
それからトラックのデザインが異なります
But its main essence is to wish to say
しかし、その主な本質はこう言いたいということです
We are anytime anywhere
私たちはいつでもどこでも
Can receive at least three or more satellites for positioning
少なくとも3つ以上の衛星を受信して​​測位可能
So why do you need three satellites?
では、なぜ 3 つの衛星が必要なのでしょうか?
Then we can use this diagram to illustrate
次に、この図を使用して説明します。
What if I'm the captain
もし私が船長だったらどうしますか
I don't know where I am now
今どこにいるのか分かりません
Then I went to receive the signal from this satellite
それから私はこの衛星からの信号を受信しに行きました
Then receive the time from the satellite signal
衛星信号から時刻を受信します
I know how far I am from this satellite
この衛星から自分がどのくらい離れているかを知っています
Let's say I'm a thousand kilometers away from this satellite
この衛星から 1,000 キロメートル離れたところにいるとしましょう
then i know
それなら私は知っています
All my positions on this ship
この船での私のすべての立場
May be anywhere on this garden boat
このガーデンボートのどこにでもあるかもしれない
But it doesn't tell me where I am
しかし、それは私がどこにいるのかを教えてくれません
So I have to go and receive the second satellite
だから私は2番目の衛星を受信しに行かなければなりません
Then hand over the other garden
そしてもう一つの庭を譲る
so i know
だから私は知っています
my location is not in this location
私の場所はこの場所ではありません
right here
ここにあります
but i want to make sure
でも確かめたい
Is it this location or this location
この場所ですか、この場所ですか
I have to accept the second satellite
2番目の衛星を受け入れなければなりません
The third WeChat signal
3 番目の WeChat シグナル
then i know
それなら私は知っています
So I'm right here
だから私はここにいる
That's why we need
だからこそ必要なのです
Three WeChat to do this navigation
このナビゲーションを行うための 3 つの WeChat
to do positioning
位置決め用
what about the fact
事実はどうですか
We have also done a lot in Taiwan
台湾でもたくさんのことをしてきました
The so-called fixed station of this GPS
このGPSのいわゆる固定局です。
Then we mainly accept
それでは主に受け付けております
This signal from the US WeChat
米国のWeChatからのこの信号
what about these
これらはどうですか
Where are these side stations?
これらの脇駅はどこにありますか？
is that we're going on a regular basis
定期的に行っているということです
to measure its coordinates
その座標を測定する
Then there is this coordinate change
次に、この座標の変更があります
we'll know
私たちは知っています
One state for each side station movement
各側局移動の状態
What about this picture?
この写真はどうでしょうか？
Different colors represent different units
異なる色は異なる単位を表します
point of color
色のポイント
The red color is from the Meteorological Bureau and the Earth Institute.
赤色は気象庁と地球研究所によるものです。
colored dots
色付きのドット
then blue is the interior
それから青はインテリアです
point of color
色のポイント
Then green is other units
緑はその他のユニットです
That's what we do wild
それが私たちがワイルドにやっていることです
Some circumstances of residence
居住環境の一部
Some of these points are called fixed stations
これらのポイントの一部は固定ステーションと呼ばれます
fixed station means
固定局の意味
It is recording data 24 hours a day
24時間データを記録しています
Instruments and antennas are left in this place
この場所には計器やアンテナが残されている
then we will be on the surface
そうすれば私たちは地上にいるでしょう
we'll fight underground
私たちは地下で戦います
then there is a stone
それから石があります
Then when we make a vegetable gallery, it is a finalized product
そして野菜ギャラリーを作ると完成品になります
and then go and measure this rocky center point
それから行って、この石の中心点を測ってください
This coordinate changes over time
この座標は時間とともに変化します
Then this one is like a mobile plant in the wild.
そして、これは野生の移動植物のようなものです。
is that it is not fixed
それは修正されていないということです
We may measure once a year
年に1回測定する場合があります
Then observe the change of this coordinate with time
次に、この座標の時間の変化を観察します。
Then, in fact, this field work is quite hard.
で、実はこの現場作業が結構大変なんです。
Then also full of horror
それからホラーも満載
I remember almost twenty years ago
二十年近く前のことを思い出します
Sometimes I go to Chiayi with my classmates
時々クラスメートと嘉義に行きます
Mei Shan Lane to do this field work
このフィールドワークを行うのはメイシャンレーンです
Then it was about three or four o'clock
それから3時か4時くらいでした
afternoon time
午後の時間
then it was almost afternoon
それからほぼ午後だった
thunderstorm rainy day very dark
雷雨雨の日はとても暗い
That's because our field survey goes once a year
それは、年に一度現地調査を行っているからです。
So the grass basically grows taller than a person
つまり、草は基本的に人の身長よりも高く成長します
Then we all have to take the knife
それならみんなでナイフを取らなければなりません
Then rummage in the grass to find our spots
それから草の中を探し回ってスポットを見つけます
Because this point is actually not very easy to find
このポイントは実際には見つけるのが簡単ではないため、
sometimes covered with soil
土で覆われていることもあります
As a result, we couldn't find it after searching for a long time.
結果、長時間探しても見つかりませんでした。
Then I separated from my classmates
それからクラスメイトとは別れた
separately to find
別々に探す
It didn't take long
それほど時間はかかりませんでした
There's a grave with a picture on it
写真が描かれたお墓があります
right at me
私に向かって
Then
それから
at that time
その時
I feel a current
流れを感じる
all the way down my spine
背骨のずっと下まで
wear to forehead
額まで着用する
Then for the first time I experienced what it means to have a chill down your spine
そのとき初めて背筋が凍るということがどういうことなのかを経験した
because then i knew
そのとき私は知っていたから
wow, it really is
うわー、本当にそうだね
It really feels like there is electricity
本当に電気が通っているような気がします
At that time, the previous life thought
その時、前世はこう思った
I really need to get out of this place
本当にここから出なければいけないんだ
Yes, okay follow up
はい、はい、フォローアップします
When I told this joke to my assistant the day before yesterday
一昨日、アシスタントにこのジョークを言ったとき
he asked me
彼は私に尋ねました
do you remember what that photo looked like
その写真がどんな感じだったか覚えていますか
I'll just talk to him
ちょっと彼と話してみます
i just don't remember
ただ覚えていないだけです
yes it's actually
はい、実際そうです
We actually have a lot of these in the wild
実際、野生にはこれらがたくさんあります
some assortment
いくつかの品揃え
Some are actually quite scary
実際にはかなり怖いものもあります
but
しかし
Even we outdoor public still have to be very careful
私たち屋外の一般人でも依然として十分な注意が必要です
Because in fact, there are often various states
実際にはさまざまな状態が存在することが多いため、
Will appear
現れる
Okay then I'll stop talking about horror
はい、ホラーの話はやめておきます
Let's move on
続けましょう
Then this is our Taiwan GPS fixed
それから、これは台湾の GPS 固定です
in our measured
私たちの測定では
The movement speed of the test battle is long
テストバトルの移動速度が長い
That's a GPS watch
それはGPSウォッチです
need time series
時系列が必要です
This is the east-west component, the north-south component and the vertical component
これは、東西成分、南北成分、垂直成分です。
So if we
それで、もし私たちが
For example, this is the record from 2004 to 2017
例えば、これは2004年から2017年までの記録です。
Then if we are doing measurements every day
毎日測定を行っていると
This is the fixed station data
固定局データです
we can get a point
私たちは点を得ることができます
Then there are long-term observations
それから長期の観察もある
We can get this time series of a motion
この時系列の動きを取得できます
Then we can do linear regression
次に、線形回帰を行うことができます
We know the speed of Ce Zhan's movement
私たちはCe Zhanの動きの速さを知っています
Then when the earthquake happened
その後、地震が起こったとき
For example, this is the Meifeng earthquake
例えば、これは梅豊地震です。
This is a battle near Guan Temple
これは関廟付近の戦いです
then you can find out
そうすれば分かるよ
when the earthquake happened
地震が起こったとき
it will result in the displacement
それはズレを生むことになる
So there will be a jump here
だからここでジャンプがあるでしょう
there will be a discontinuity
不連続性が生じるだろう
Then there will be some post-earthquake displacement
その後、地震後の変位が発生するだろう
Then slowly it will return to
それからゆっくりと元に戻ります
It is the relatively linear one before the earthquake.
地震前は比較的直線的でした。
a state of motion
運動状態
then we can use this information
その後、この情報を使用できます
to do a lot later
後でたくさんやること
It is some follow-up research work
追跡調査の仕事です
Well, besides these, this global navigation satellite positioning system
さて、これらのほかに、この全地球航法衛星測位システム
We can also use this
これも使えます
Core Aperture Mirror Radar Gamma Layer
コア アパーチャ ミラー レーダー ガンマ層
sound appreciation
音の鑑賞
The English name is here
英語名はこちら
Basically it is also a data using satellite
基本的には衛星を利用したデータでもあります
So this is where the satellites fly
ここが衛星が飛んでいる場所です
Then it has a
それから、それは
This one can sweep the floor
これで床掃除ができる
It uses the radar slope to sweep a feature on the surface
レーダーの傾斜を使用して地表上のフィーチャをスイープします
And because of the scan time difference?
スキャン時間の違いのせいでしょうか？
I know this direction
この方向性は知っています
From satellite to any point on the surface
衛星から地表上のあらゆる地点まで
Then I can know the distance in this direction
そうすれば、この方向の距離がわかります
The amount of change
変化量
Let's say there's a volcano here
ここに火山があるとしましょう
What about when you sweep the terrain?
地形を掃除するときはどうでしょうか？
Its shape is like this
その形はこんな感じです
but behind
でも後ろに
Because the volcano has produced some deformation
火山が多少の変形を起こしているため
What about during the second sweep?
2回目の掃引中はどうなるでしょうか？
It has a difference amount to the bit
ビットまでの差額がある
Then you can have this bitwise difference amount
次に、このビットごとの差額を取得できます
To calculate is along the
計算するのは、
How big is the deformation depending on the direction of the satellite?
衛星の向きによる変形はどのくらいですか?
Then this is what we use
それから、これが私たちが使うものです
synthetic aperture
合成開口
Radar interferometry data
レーダー干渉計データ
Go Sweep Out During Beauty Earthquake
ビューティー地震のときに掃討に行く
These deformed strips around
周りの変形したストリップ
These are the changes in phase
これらは位相の変化です
We can take it and go through some calculations
それを受け取って、いくつかの計算を行ってみましょう
Convert it to the potential of the ground resonance on the east and west
東西の地盤共鳴電位に換算
vertical position
垂直位置
then you can see that
そうすればそれがわかります
In the words of beauty earthquake
美地震の言葉で
In the market near Guanmiao
関廟近くの市場にて
TSMC has more than 10 cm on the market
TSMCは10cm以上を市場に出しています
It's actually pretty big
実はかなり大きいんです
There is some deformation of about 5 to 10 cm in the horizontal volume
横ボリュームに5～10cm程度の変形がございます。
What I just talked about are some more realistic observation methods.
今お話ししたのは、より現実的な観察方法です。
So if we want to know about some older earthquakes
したがって、古い地震について知りたい場合は、
we have to rely on the sea
私たちは海に頼らなければなりません
For example, Haijie
たとえば、ハイジ
There are many seashores like these in eastern Taiwan
台湾東部にはこのような海岸がたくさんあります
For example, the stone ladder is leveled.
たとえば、石梯子は平らにされます。
This is some research done by a Japanese research team in Taiwan
これは台湾の日本の研究チームによって行われた研究です
Then this is Haijie near Shitiping
それからここは石頂坪の近くの海街です
Then it goes from the lowest level to the highest level
その後、最低レベルから最高レベルに進みます
About 20 meters away
約20メートル離れたところ
then it has several stages
それからいくつかの段階があります
The geologists are going to collect some rocks on this base
地質学者はこの基地でいくつかの岩石を収集する予定です
then do research
それから研究をしてください
They know the history of these grounding platforms
彼らはこれらの接地プラットフォームの歴史を知っています
Some of the history of these platform depths are related to the rise and fall of the sea level
これらのプラットフォームの深さの歴史の一部は、海面の上昇と下降に関連しています。
Some are related to the depth of the earth
地球の深さに関係するものもあります
They have to do some progressive analysis
彼らは進歩的な分析を行う必要がある
like this beautiful grounding
この美しいグラウンディングのように
Can do some related follow-up research work
関連する追跡調査作業を行うことができます
In addition to coastal grounding, you can also use the belt area
沿岸接地に加えて、ベルトエリアも使用できます
coral reef
サンゴ礁
Coral reefs are actually coral reefs because it only grows below sea level
サンゴ礁は海面下でのみ成長するため、実際にはサンゴ礁です
So we can take advantage of this condition
したがって、この条件を利用することができます
Go see how we use coral reefs to record the history of earthquakes
地震の歴史を記録するためにサンゴ礁がどのように使われているかを見に行きましょう
This records the growth process of a coral reef
サンゴ礁の成長過程を記録します。
this is how high it grows and this is the time
これがどれほど高く成長するか、そして今がその時です
Then the coral reef slowly grows taller
そしてサンゴ礁はゆっくりと背を高くしていきます
so you can see it growing higher and higher
そうすればどんどん高くなっていくのがわかるだろう
getting higher over time
時間の経過とともに高くなる
at this time if there is
現時点であれば
It can't grow taller after it touches the sea level
海面に達すると身長は伸びません
it can only grow sideways
横にしか成長できない
So its height is to maintain the video
その高さはビデオを維持することです
But what if there is an event that causes the sea floor to collapse?
しかし、海底が崩壊するような出来事が起こったらどうなるでしょうか?
Basically, the growth height of these coral gums behind it will be shorter than the original ones.
基本的に、その後ろのサンゴゴムの成長高さは、元のものよりも低くなります。
And what if there's a seismic event that causes the sea floor to appear?
そして、海底が現れる地震が起きたらどうなるでしょうか?
The height of the coral glue that grows behind it can be higher than the one that came before
後ろに成長するサンゴ接着剤の高さは、以前のものよりも高くなる可能性があります
OK so we can go to these screens nearby
OK、近くのこれらの画面に移動できます
Find these large coral gels
大きなサンゴのゲルを見つけてください
Then we cut it open, and after cutting it open
それから切り開いて、切り開いた後
You take some of these samples for dating
あなたはデートのためにこれらのサンプルのいくつかを採取します
Then go and see, that is, when
それから行って見てください、つまり、いつですか
It has some, for example, massive die-off of coral gum
たとえば、サンゴゴムの大規模な死滅などがあります。
Then it may be related to some earthquake events
それなら、それはいくつかの地震イベントに関連しているかもしれません
Then use this to find some older earthquake events
次に、これを使用して古い地震イベントを検索します。
Well, if the earthquake is big enough, we can actually directly
そうですね、地震が十分に大きい場合は、実際に直接被害を受ける可能性があります。
Measure the amount of coral gel and we'll know
サンゴジェルの量を測ればわかります
How much vertical displacement did the earthquake produce at this location
この場所で地震によりどのくらいの鉛直変位が生じたのか
This is after the 2004 Sumada Earthquake
これは2004年のスマトラ島地震後のことです
Everyone can see that
誰もがそれを見ることができます
All coral reefs are lifted above sea level
すべてのサンゴ礁は海面よりも高く持ち上げられます
Then we can directly measure
そうすれば直接測定できます
Because of the vertical displacement caused by the earthquake
地震による鉛直変位の影響で
Then this is a coral reef to measure
それから、これは測定するサンゴ礁です
2005 scale 8.6
2005規模8.6
Vertical Displacement Caused by the Great Sumata Earthquake
寸又大地震による鉛直変位
The position of zero deformation is at this place
変形ゼロの位置はこの場所です
Coral reefs from this line to the creek are all uplifted
このラインから小川までのサンゴ礁はすべて隆起しています
The maximum lift is up to 2.5 meters
最大リフトは2.5メートルまでです
Edom is offline
エドムはオフラインです
The largest drop is up to 1 meter
最大の落下は1メートルまで
That lift should be a good amount
そのリフトはかなりの量になるはずです
But those who are offline may have to dive to measure
ただし、オフラインの人は測定するためにダイビングする必要があるかもしれません
so do the work
だから仕事をしなさい
In fact, as you can imagine, it is very hard work.
実際、ご想像のとおり、それは非常に大変な作業です。
that apart from coral reef observation
サンゴ礁観察以外にも
We just could use this GPS
この GPS を使えばいいだけです
This is the global satellite positioning system
これは全地球規模の衛星測位システムです
To measure the coseismic displacement of the Banshui earthquake
播水地震の余震変位を測定する
For example, the red line
たとえば、赤い線
It was during the 2005 earthquake
それは2005年の地震のときでした
The displacement of the surface on both sides of it
表面の両側の変位
The largest is actually nearly 4 meters
最大のものは実際には4メートル近くあります
Then with these observations
次に、これらの観察を踏まえて
Next we're going to see
次に見ていきます
How do we get from these surface observations
これらの表面観察からどのように得られるのか
to understand the behavior of the fault's activity
障害のアクティビティの動作を理解するため
Then we can actually use a very simple theory
次に、実際に非常に単純な理論を使用できます。
Let me explain to you
説明させてください
It is a model of semi-wireless space
セミワイヤレス空間のモデルです
because assuming this is us
なぜなら、これが私たちだと仮定すると
It is a deformed appearance observed on the surface
表面に観察される変形した外観です
Then scientists know that
科学者たちはそれを知っています
Where might the underground fault be located?
地下断層はどこにある可能性がありますか?
Then we know that
そうすれば、私たちはそれを知ります
on that fault
そのせいで
If there is a dislocation of the unit on the fault of the unit
ユニットの故障によりユニットの位置ずれがあった場合
anywhere on the earth
地球上のどこにでも
How big will be the horizontal and vertical differences
水平方向と垂直方向の差はどのくらいになりますか
So our job is to find a combination
したがって、私たちの仕事は組み合わせを見つけることです
This combination actually has different forms of Huayi
この組み合わせには実際にはさまざまな形の華義があります
Let's see how we can go
どうやって行くか見てみましょう
Fitting Observations to the Surface
観察結果を表面に当てはめる
This is a reverse process
これは逆のプロセスです
Then we can go back to calculate
その後、計算に戻ります
The Situation of Chinese Americans on the Fault Level
過失レベルでの中国系アメリカ人の状況
what about this
これはどうですか
that we are first
私たちが最初であるということ
Need to know the geometry of the fault
断層の形状を知る必要がある
that fault geometry
その断層形状
We can know from the distribution of earthquakes
地震の分布からわかる
for example
例えば
This is in the Sumata region
ここは寸又地域です
A case of earthquake distribution
地震分布の事例
Then we will draw a profi
それからプロファイを描きます
then we know
そうすればわかります
The distribution of this earthquake
今回の地震の分布
distribution of a collection space
コレクションスペースの配布
then we know
そうすればわかります
Possible Situation Angles of Faults
考えられる状況 断層の角度
For example, the latent layer may be slower
たとえば、潜在層は遅くなる可能性があります。
Humidity Deep places are steeper
湿度 深いところは急勾配になる
then we can
それならできます
Apply the geometry using this fault
この断層を使用してジオメトリを適用します
then calculate
それから計算します
The distribution of its ethnic Chinese on the fault level
断層レベルでの中国人の分布
The red and yellow room is
赤と黄色の部屋は
The number of Chinese on this fault level
この障害レベルにある中国人の数
projected onto the surface of a
の表面に投影される
is a distribution
ディストリビューションです
and black
そして黒
is our observation
私たちの観察です
that pink words
そのピンクの言葉
is the predicted value of our model
はモデルの予測値です
then you can see this
そうすればこれを見ることができます
In fact, the fit is pretty good.
実際、フィット感はかなり良いです。
then we know
そうすればわかります
In this 2005 earthquake
この2005年の地震では
its setback
その挫折
Nearly at least 12 meters of setback
少なくとも12メートル近くのセットバック
What about after the third?
3回目以降はどうでしょうか？
Actually
実際
these have been
これらはありました
Many of these book exhibitions in this disaster area
この被災地での書籍展示の多くは
in fact there will be
実際にはあるでしょう
There will also be a situation of continuous motion
継続的に動作する状況も発生します
That's mainly because some energy
それは主にエネルギーがあるからです
Not fully released during the earthquake
地震時に完全に解放されなかった
So it will have a case of actively moving
なので積極的に動くケースもあるでしょう
For example, in this Raiva book exhibition
たとえば、このライヴァの本の展示では
This is the time of the earthquake
地震の時です
After that earthquake you can find that it has a
その地震の後、それが起こっていることがわかります。
A variation of the direct decay
直接減衰のバリエーション
very strong change
非常に強い変化
Then finally stabilized slowly
その後、徐々に安定してきました
slower again
また遅くなる
then this is
それならこれは
Beeson's book exhibition
ビーソンの本展
with Samp
サンプル付き
it has the same
それは同じです
That is, it will deform rapidly after the earthquake
つまり、地震後に急激に変形する
Then slowly it will return to
それからゆっくりと元に戻ります
It is at the speed of deformation before the earthquake
地震前の変形速度です
This is the so-called exact deformation
これがいわゆる正確な変形です
Then we will introduce to you
それではご紹介させていただきます
It is this screen bag near Taiwan
台湾近郊のこちらのスクリーンバッグです
This is the structure of a ground near the screen strip in Taiwan
これは台湾のスクリーンストリップ近くの地面の構造です
Because Taiwan is located at the junction of the Eurasian plate and the Philippine Sea plate
台湾はユーラシアプレートとフィリピン海プレートの境目に位置しているため、
Off the northeastern coast of Taiwan, the Philippine Sea Plate follows the Ryeball Trench
台湾の北東海岸沖では、フィリピン海プレートがライボール海溝に続いています
Then the screen goes under the Eurasian plate
そして画面はユーラシアプレートの下に潜ります
To the south is the Eurasian plate along the Mara Trench
南にはマラ海溝に沿ったユーラシアプレートがあります
Screen to the bottom of the Philippine Binghai plate
フィリピン海プレートの底までのスクリーン
Then the heavy bone fault in eastern Taiwan is the wind and belt of these two plates
台湾東部の重い骨断層は、これら 2 つのプレートの風とベルトです。
To the east of the heavy bone fault is the Philippine Sea plate
重い骨断層の東にはフィリピン海プレートがあります
To the west is the Eurasian plate
西にはユーラシアプレートがあります
Because Taiwan's rate of plate aggregation in this place
この場所は台湾のプレート集積率が高いため、
In fact, it can be as high as 90 meters on average
実際、平均すると高さは90メートルに達することもあります
Then in the south and north are the main screens
そして南と北にはメインスクリーンがあります
In the middle is the collision
真ん中が衝突です
So Taiwan will have a mountain with a height of nearly 4 kilometers
つまり台湾には高さ4キロメートル近い山があることになる
It's here that in fact it's collision-based
実際に衝突ベースであるのはここです
Next to it, there are actually two very large screen strips
その隣には、実際には非常に大きなスクリーン ストリップが 2 つあります。
So we have to evaluate
したがって、評価する必要があります
Will there be a big screen with earthquakes near Taiwan in the future?
将来、台湾付近で地震に関する大画面が上映されるでしょうか？
So what is this? Over the past 100 years?
では、これは何でしょうか? 過去 100 年間でしょうか?
Some Major Earthquakes Near Taiwan
台湾付近で大規模な地震が発生
Then here are some earthquakes with the scale of Six Flags
次に、シックス・フラッグス級の地震をいくつか紹介します。
Then the color represents the depth of the earthquake
色は地震の深さを表します
Then the bigger the earthquake the bigger the circle
そうすると、地震が大きければ大きいほど、円も大きくなります
What about the past hundred years?
過去百年はどうなったでしょうか？
The main earthquake can be seen off the coast of Ryukyu
琉球沖で本震が確認できる
with the eastern seas of Taiwan
台湾の東の海と
There were also some big earthquakes on that land
その土地でも大きな地震が何度かありました
But compared with the earthquakes in the Ryukyu Sea Country, there are relatively few
しかし、琉球海の国の地震に比べれば比較的少ないです。
The largest earthquake was a magnitude 7.7 earthquake in 1920
最大の地震は 1920 年に発生したマグニチュード 7.7 の地震でした。
Near Lake Ryukyu
琉球湖付近
Are there some tsunami events near Taiwan?
台湾付近で津波が発生していますか?
that's true
それは本当だ
Because Japanese scholars have investigated some
日本の学者がいくつか調べたので、
Some information on the lake on Ryukyu Island
琉球島の湖に関する情報
found in 1771
1771年に発見
This year, in fact, the subsurface layer of the Ryukyu Trench may have a rupture of the subsurface layer.
実は今年、琉球海溝の地下層の破壊が起こる可能性があります。
Generating a Turtle Baa Earthquake
亀バア地震を発生させる
In fact, the Kameo Hachia earthquake was
実際、カメオハチア地震は、
caused these tsunamis to be seen near these islands
これらの島の近くでこれらの津波が見られる原因となった
The height of the tsunami was actually more than 30 meters
実際の津波の高さは30メートル以上だった
So it's actually pretty impressive
それで実際にはかなり印象的です
Then there is the Mara Trench
それからマラ海溝があります
The Mara Trench actually extends to the south of Taiwan to the Philippines
マラ海溝は実際には台湾の南からフィリピンまで広がっています
That's because Luzon was colonized by Spain in the 17th century
それはルソン島が17世紀にスペインの植民地だったからです。
Then we read in the past
それから、私たちは過去に読んだ
It is the data of these past histories
これらの過去履歴のデータです
In fact, for the past 400 years he
実際、過去 400 年間、彼は
There is no earthquake in this hidden vine belt
この隠れた蔓地帯には地震はない
But will it happen in the future
しかし、将来的にはそうなるのでしょうか
In fact, there is a lot of uncertainty
実は不確定要素が多い
Just like the 2004 Sumatra earthquake
2004年のスマトラ沖地震と同じように
The Sumada earthquake, the earthquake in that place started online
須磨田地震、あの場所の地震はオンラインで始まった
In fact, about a thousand years ago
実は今から約千年前、
So what do you say in this
それで、これで何と言っていますか
Although this place has not had a major earthquake in the past 400 years
ここは過去400年間大きな地震がなかったのに
But we cannot rule out that it will not have a major earthquake in the future
しかし、今後大地震が起こらない可能性も否定できません。
So we still have to study some deformation behaviors in this place
したがって、この場所の変形挙動についてはまだ研究する必要があります。
Then let's introduce the Ryukyu Trench first.
それでは、まずは琉球海溝についてご紹介しましょう。
Because the Ryukyu Trench is relatively tight
琉球海溝は比較的狭いため
This is what happened when the earthquake collapsed off the coast of northeastern Taiwan
台湾北東部沖で地震が起きたとき、こうなった
Lighter colors are shallower earthquakes
明るい色は浅い地震です
Deeper is a deeper earthquake
深いほど深い地震です
so you can see what the screen does
画面の動作がわかるように
if we go from here
ここから行くなら
This is an instant noodle from the Ryukyu Trench
琉球海溝のインスタントラーメンです
You can see the distribution of these earthquakes generated by the plate screen
プレートスクリーンで発生した地震の分布がわかります
Then we can use these in eastern Taiwan
そうすれば台湾東部でも使えるようになります
Velocity yields of crustal deformation observed on land
陸上で観測される地殻変動の速度降伏
to calculate is to say
計算するということは、
Will there be a major earthquake in this place in the future?
将来この場所で大地震が起こるでしょうか？
if it had a big earthquake
もし大きな地震が起きたら
what its possible ruptured form looks like
破裂した可能性のある形状はどのように見えるか
the magnitude of the earthquake it can produce
それが引き起こす可能性のある地震の規模
what a situation
どういう状況だ
Because our strategy is all on land
なぜなら私たちの戦略はすべて陸上にあるからです
So in fact we can probably say that
したがって実際にはおそらく次のように言えます
closer to the coast
海岸に近い
It's actually possible for energy to build up here
実はここにエネルギーが溜まる可能性がある
But we have no way to speculate that
しかし、それを推測する方法はありません
How long will its rupture range extend?
破裂範囲はどこまで伸びるのでしょうか？
The reference here is mainly to refer to the distribution of earthquakes.
ここでの言及は主に地震の分布を指します。
Because now is the flow of the last generation
今は先代の流れだから
Between the Peaceful Basin and the Nahai Basin
ピースフル盆地とナハイ盆地の間
There is a very dense earthquake bill
非常に濃い地震法案があります
So we think the area where it broke may be this area
したがって、壊れたエリアはこのエリアである可能性があると考えられます
According to some empirical formulas of seismologists
地震学者のいくつかの経験式によると
We know the likely rupture area of ​​an earthquake
地震の破壊可能範囲がわかっている
Let's say the length is 120 kilometers
長さが120キロだとしましょう
Then the width is 70 km
そうすると幅は70kmです
then we can calculate its earthquake size
そうすれば地震の規模を計算できます
Probably around 7.5 to 8
たぶん7.5～8くらい
But if we use another method
しかし、別の方法を使用すると、
Assume that the earthquakes here have a period of 1500 years
ここでの地震の周期が 1500 年であると仮定します。
Then it was broken into a loss rate of 86 meters.
その後、損失率86メートルに突入しました。
The largest scale is 8.6
最大スケールは8.6
The largest scale mentioned here means
ここでいう最大規模とは、
All the energy accumulated here
ここに溜まったすべてのエネルギー
Released once by an earthquake
地震により一度解放
Of course, if it has many earthquakes
もちろん地震が多ければ
release these energies slowly
これらのエネルギーをゆっくりと解放してください
Then maybe it won't be this big
そうしたらここまで大きくならないかもしれない
will be smaller
小さくなります
So let's use this cracked paper model to see
それでは、このひび割れた紙モデルを使って見てみましょう
If such an earthquake occurs in this place
もしこの場所でそんな地震が起きたら
what kind of behavior
どのような行動ですか
good
良い
please wait
お待ちください
Okay, this is the model we just used
さて、これは先ほど持っていたモデルを使用しています
to calculate
計算する
If the earthquake happened
もし地震が起こったら
what harm will it do
それはどんな害を及ぼしますか
here represents this
ここはこれを表します
The velocity of a positive wave passing through a
物体を通過する正の波の速度
Then this side represents the wave height generated by the tsunami
するとこの辺が津波によって発生する波高を表します
then you can see
そうすればわかります
The seismic waves of this tsunami travel first
この津波の地震波が最初に伝わります
The tsunami was generated after the transmission
津波は発信後に発生した
And then this tsunami will do a lot of damage all over the east coast
そうすれば、この津波は東海岸全域に大きな被害を与えるでしょう
The maximum breaking height can reach about 4 meters
最大破壊高さは約4メートルに達する可能性があります
You can see this is
これはわかります
The shooting range is about 2 meters to 4 meters
射撃範囲は約2メートルから4メートルです
along this eastern coast
この東海岸沿いに
In fact, there are quite a few changes
実はかなりの変更点があります
And what about the tsunami?
そして津波はどうなるのでしょうか？
Ship bypassing Taiwan to the Taiwan Strait
台湾を迂回して台湾海峡に向かう船
A case of boat waves
船の波の場合
and what about the east
そして東はどうでしょうか
There is still some back and forth
まだ多少の前後はありますが
Because of the back and forth shock of the tsunami waves
津波の前後の衝撃のため
Then what
じゃあ何
can see this
これを見ることができます
In fact there are almost 2 to 4 meters of some
実際には2～4メートル近くあるものもある。
Brogao will clean these places
Brogao はこれらの場所を掃除します
then go around
それから回ってください
to the Taiwan Strait
台湾海峡へ
That's because the main rupture direction of this earthquake
それは、今回の地震の主な破壊方向が
is the direction of the Pacific Ocean
太平洋の方向です
So in fact, for western Taiwan,
実際、台湾西部では、
Its harm is less obvious
その害はあまり明らかではありません
but in the east
でも東では
In fact its impact is quite significant
実際、その影響はかなり大きいです
This is probably a tsunami boat
これはおそらく津波船です
Situation of transmission
発信状況
This is what our earth
これは私たちの地球が作ったものです
Provided by Li Xianzhong Associate Research Institute
提供：李賢中准研究院
next we will see
次に見てみましょう
us
私たち
how do scientists know
科学者はどうやって知るのか
Has there ever been a tsunami in this place?
この場所に津波があったことがありますか?
how do we study these tsunamis
これらの津波をどのように研究するか
older events of these tsunamis
これらの津波の古い出来事
There are several methods
いくつかの方法があります
For example we can go
たとえば、私たちは行くことができます
these seaside to do some
この海辺で何かをするために
sampling work
サンプリング作業
To see the distribution of these grades
これらのグレードの分布を確認するには
then go see say
それから見に行って言う
Is this related to the tsunami?
これは津波と関係があるのでしょうか？
Tsunami-related grades
津波関連グレード
otherwise we can go to the beach
そうでなければビーチに行けるよ
Find these very large boulders
非常に大きな岩を見つけてください
Because such a large rock
こんなに大きな岩なので、
it's no way through that
それは無理だ
It's just that these waves go
ただこの波が去っていくだけだ
move to shore
岸に移動する
Usually it's ten dollars
通常は10ドルです
or typhoon
または台風
Or a tsunami
それとも津波か
to be transported to the coast
海岸まで運ばれる
So scientists can go and find
科学者たちが行って見つけられるように
just to collect some
いくつか集めるためだけに
some samples for dating
デート用のサンプル
Then learned that he was relocated to
その後、彼が転勤したことを知りました
The terrain of this coast
この海岸の地形
then go and see say
それから行って見て言う
Is he with some
彼は誰かと一緒ですか
Events that implicitly bring about earthquakes are related
暗黙的に地震を引き起こす出来事には関連性がある
what about other than that
それ以外はどうですか？
It is to rely on historical documents to record now
今を記録するのは史料に頼ることだ
For example, Taiwan
たとえば、台湾
There are also some records of tsunamis
いくつかの津波も記録されています
Most definitely dated to 1867
最も確実に1867年のものである
in Keelung?
基隆では？
There was once a tsunami event
かつて津波があった
There are some historical records over here
ここには歴史的な記録がいくつかあります
Then everyone can take a look
そしたらみんなも見てね
that's the reaction here
それがここでの反応です
That is to say, the water in the port recedes
つまり、港の水が引くのです。
until all the fish move in mud or water
すべての魚が泥や水の中に移動するまで
struggle with
と格闘する
And what about these fathers, daughters and children?
そして、これらの父親、娘、子供たちはどうですか？
just go and run
ただ行って走ってください
to examine this baby's gift
この赤ちゃんの贈り物を調べるために
Then what
じゃあ何
The results of it
その結果
What about sea water?
海水はどうでしょうか？
first back
最初に戻る
A very important feature of a tsunami is that the sea water will recede first
津波の非常に重要な特徴は、海水が最初に後退することです。
and then it will come back
そしてそれは戻ってくるでしょう
And when you come back, the height is very high
そして戻ってくると、高さがとても高くなります
Then there will be a great disaster
そうなると大きな災いが起こるだろう
Then this world is recorded in historical documents
そしてこの世界は歴史文書に記録される
That except in this English literature
この英語文献以外では
The world is made in Tamsui Hall
世界は淡水ホールで作られる
And there are records in the world
そして世界には記録があります
That is to say, there were some tsunami incidents at that time
つまり、当時、いくつかの津波事故があったということです。
Then hundreds of people died like this
その後、何百人もの人がこのようにして亡くなりました
Then we can also learn from these historical Christian districts
そうすれば、私たちはこれらの歴史的なキリスト教地区から学ぶこともできます
Find records of these tsunamis
津波の記録を探す
Then we based on the description of these historical documents
次に、これらの歴史的文書の記述に基づいて、
Go see this site where these tsunamis have occurred in the past
過去に津波が発生したこの場所を見に行ってください
where is it now
今日はどこですか
Then we make it beautiful
それから私たちはそれを美しくします
Then slowly go to find
それからゆっくり探しに行きます
what was the source of the possible tsunami
津波の原因は何だったのか
besides these
これらのほかに
Like the archaeological team of Academia Sinica and National Taiwan University in Keelung North
基隆北にある中央研究院と国立台湾大学の考古学チームのように
They just do some research on cultural chairs
彼らは文化的な椅子についていくつかの研究を行っているだけです
Then they found out during their investigation that
その後、彼らは調査中に次のことを発見しました。
Like this Uni3 this
このUni3のようにこれ
this grade level
この学年レベル
it's a walrus
それはセイウチです
high-concentration water-like
高濃度の水のようなもの
formed by an accumulation
一個堆積作用所形成
So maybe it has something to do with the tsunami
津波と関係があるのか​​もしれない
So scientists can actually do
それで科学者は実際にできるのです
Grass hook
挖草鉤
Then go to the source of these grades
次に、これらのグレードのソースに移動します
and then speculate that
そして次のように推測します
what grades
何級
Maybe it's related to the tsunami
もしかしたら津波と関係があるかもしれない
Those same technologies are in fact
それらと同じテクノロジーが実際には
can also be used for this
これにも使用できます
Some of the inbound faults
受信障害の一部
repeat cycle
重複周期
The response cycle is a
応答サイクルは、
some studies like this
このような研究もある
Then we introduce this
それではこれを紹介します
after the ryukyu screen bag
琉球スクリーンバッグのあと
Next we're going to look at Mara Screen Bags
次に、Mara Screen Bagsを見てみましょう。
That mara screen bag in fact
実はそのマラスクリーンバッグ
In fact, it is quite far from Taiwan.
実は台湾からはかなり遠いんです。
yes
はい
It actually starts from the south of Taiwan
実は台湾の南から始まります
stretches all the way to luzon
ルソン島まで続く
But should we pay attention to it
しかし、それに注意を払うべきでしょうか
we really need to pay attention to it
私たちは本当にそれに注意を払う必要があります
Because if a relatively large rupture tsunami occurs here,
ここで比較的大きな破壊津波が発生すると、
just go this way
ただここに行ってください
If the boat over here
もしボートがここにあるなら
will cause mainland China
中国本土を引き起こすだろう
Vietnam on the southeast coast
ベトナム南東海岸
Then many countries in Southeast Asia
それから東南アジアの多くの国
will be implicated
巻き込まれるだろう
What about the tsunami, hit it and bounce back
津波はどうだ、ぶつかって跳ね返る
For those who dive into the sea in the west of Taiwan
台湾西部の海に飛び込む方へ
These are the cities on the coast
これらは海岸沿いの都市です
In fact, there will be some great influence
実は大きな影響があるのです
Then everyone can see that
そうすれば誰もがそれを見ることができます
This plate goes to the river data to follow in Taiwan
このプレートは台湾の河川データを追跡します
A little more than here near Taiwan
ここよりもう少し、台湾に近いところ
About 92 mimiteps one or two
約 92 ミミテップ 1 または 2
In addition to this place
この場所以外にも
This big one with foam
泡が入ったこの大きなもの
big this drowning fault
この水没の断層は大きい
It actually also has a
実際には、
In the Philippines there is a large this China fault
フィリピンには中国の大きな責任がある
Philippine fault
フィリピン断層
Then this fault is also a
そうすると、この欠点もまた、
A very dangerous fault
非常に危険な故障
Then let's focus on this today
それでは今日はこれに焦点を当てましょう
Mala shadow tape
マラシャドウテープ
Then this is across this shadow foam belt
それから、これはこのシャドウフォームベルトの向こう側です
The distribution of earthquakes
地震の分布
That color represents the depth of different earthquakes
その色はさまざまな地震の深さを表します
The red ones are relatively shallow earthquakes
赤いのは比較的浅い地震です
Then the blue purple is a deeper earthquake
すると青紫はさらに深い地震です
That's different profi
それならこれは別のプロフィールです
Then I took 3 to 5 today
それで今日は3から5を取りました
Let me show you these instant noodles
このインスタントラーメンを紹介しましょう
You can clearly see this
これははっきりとわかります
Shadow Foam's Angle
シャドーフォームの角度
slowly change
ゆっくりと変化する
In fact, it has turned into a collision effect here.
実際、ここでは衝突エフェクトになっています。
In fact our earth
実は私たちの地球
As long as in 1996, in fact, a lot of observation work has been done in Brigade
実際、1996 年以来、旅団では多くの観測活動が行われてきました。
This picture is from about 20 years ago
この写真は20年くらい前のものです
We did some GPS work over here
ここで GPS の作業を行いました
This is the GPS level speed we obtained
これは私たちが取得したGPSレベルの速度です
Relative to this point the velocity of the factory
この点に対する工場の速度
This is the vertical speed factory
ここは垂直速度工場です
We use these GPS observations
これらの GPS 観測を使用します
Let's reverse the distribution of Chinese on this fault line
この断層線上の中国人の分布を逆転させましょう
This is the result we got
これが得られた結果です
We can get a so-called plate of Orheb
いわゆるオルヘブのプレートを手に入れることができます
Plate Orheb it's actually a fault rate for Chinese descent
プレート・オーヘブ、実際は中国系の過失割合だ
Divided by the long-term Chinese rate
中国の長期金利で割った値
So if this value is higher
したがって、この値が高ければ
Represents the growing likelihood of a major rupture
大規模な破断の可能性が高まっていることを表す
if smaller
小さければ
It is safer in comparison
それに比べれば安全です
So we have provided two models here
ここでは 2 つのモデルを提供しました
blue represents
青は表します
Faults are usually in the state of creeping
断層は通常、忍び寄る状態にあります
So keep releasing energy
だからエネルギーを放出し続ける
is a relatively safe state
比較的安全な状態です
the red area
赤いエリア
This means it belongs to a locked state
これはロック状態に属していることを意味します
That is to say, a big earthquake in the future
つまり、将来大地震が起こるということです。
It is possible for a relatively large rupture
比較的大きな断裂が起こる可能性がある
that black arrow
あの黒い矢
It means that when an earthquake occurs in the future
つまり、将来地震が起きたとき、
These curations of the possible surface
可能性のある表面のこれらのキュレーション
a way of movement
移動方法
Then we can use these
次に、これらを使用できます
surface data area to invert
反転する表面データ領域
In fact, our model
実際、私たちのモデルは
because we entered the trench
塹壕に入ったので
In fact it's not obvious
実際には明らかではない
Not a good few observation points
観察ポイントはあまり多くありません
So in fact we're near the trench
つまり、実際に私たちは塹壕の近くにいるのです
Our model resolution
モデルの解像度
actually not very good
実際にはあまり良くありません
Therefore, in addition to making observations on land,
そのため、陸上での観測だけでなく、
In fact, we also have to go
実は私たちも行かなければなりません
Observing these behaviors of these deformations on the seabed
海底の変形の様子を観察する
Then I will introduce
それでは紹介していきます
The way our planet is going to develop now
私たちがこれから地球をどのように開発していくのか
The first one is sea floor geodesy.
一つ目は海底の測地学です。
The seabed geodesy is actually
海底測地学は実際には
Integrated GPS satellite positioning system
統合型 GPS 衛星測位システム
Positioning with deep wave
深い波動でのポジショニング
For example, we have to be on the seabed
たとえば、私たちは海底にいなければなりません。
place these deep wave transponders
これらの深波トランスポンダーを配置します
Then we go out with fishing boats
それから漁船で出かけます
We will put these GPS on the fishing boat
このGPSを漁船に搭載します
these observatories
これらの天文台
Then what
じゃあ何
This fishing boat compared to
この漁船と比べると
The location of any GPS point on land
陸上の GPS ポイントの位置
You can use the commonly used dynamic positioning
一般的に使用される動的位置決めを使用できます
to get
取得するため
what about
どうですか
fishing boats on the seabed
海底の漁船
relative position
相対位置
It is to use deep wave positioning to obtain
ディープウェーブポジショニングを使用して取得することです
In this way we can know that
このようにして、私たちはそれを知ることができます
any point on the seabed
海底のどの地点でも
Ways of motion relative to land
地面に対する動き方
what about now
今はどう
we are on the ground
私たちは地上にいる
On our planet we now have two proving grounds
私たちの地球上には現在 2 つの試験場があります
One is in the far south of the Okinawa tide
一つは沖縄の潮のはるか南にある
The water depth is about 1300 meters
水深は約1300メートル
The other one is in Ryukyu
もう一つは琉球です
Near the Ryukyu Trench
琉球海溝付近
The water depth is about 3800 meters
水深は約3800メートル
Then this study is actually a
それでは、この研究は実際には、
It takes a lot of time and money to research
研究には膨大な時間と費用がかかる
because we have to observe
私たちは観察しなければならないから
long enough for some good
良いことをするのに十分な長さ
Research results can come out
研究成果が出てくる可能性もある
What does the deep wave responder look like
ディープウェーブレスポンダーはどのようなものですか
Throw these instruments into the sea
これらの器具を海に投げ込みます
it is not recyclable
リサイクルできません
So we have to be in
だから私たちは入らなければなりません
Before the battery runs out
電池が切れる前に
Do research every year as much as possible
可能な限り毎年調査を行う
Then get the most of these observations
これらの観察を最大限に活用してください
That's the case with our Offshore Instrumentation Department.
当社のオフショア計装部門も同様です。
And then we also have to measure the seawater
それから海水も測定しなければなりません
compare its conductivity
導電性を比較する
parameters such as temperature and pressure
温度や圧力などのパラメータ
Because when we are doing deep wave positioning
なぜなら、深波測位を行っているときは
The speed at which this deep wave travels
この深い波が伝わる速さ
are related to these parameters
これらのパラメータに関連しています
So we also have to measure the relevant
したがって、関連するものも測定する必要があります
These physical parameters
これらの物理パラメータ
Then it's time to do our positioning
次に、ポジショニングを行う時間です
do some commissioning
試運転をする
That's when doing research
それは研究をしているときです
In some states using various transfer funds
一部の州ではさまざまな送金資金を使用しています
In fact, doing this research is also very hard.
実際、この調査を行うのも非常に困難です。
Because it is mainly because of the signal of the deep wave
主に深層波の信号によるものですので
it will be affected by the sound of the engine on this boat
このボートのエンジン音の影響を受けるでしょう
So usually we're doing
それで、通常私たちはやっています
when doing this research
この研究をするとき
Just drive the boat to our target area
目的のエリアまでボートを運転するだけです
Then turn off the engine and start drifting
エンジンを切ってドリフトを始めます
And then everyone is on 24-hour shifts
そして全員が24時間勤務です
and then go record those signals
そしてそれらの信号を記録しに行きます
So what we usually do is
それで、私たちが普段やっているのは、
24 hours is a shift, you have to go all the time
24 時間シフトなので、常に出勤しなければなりません
Constantly read data
常にデータを読み取る
and what about the staff
そしてスタッフはどうですか
have to endure the harsh working environment on board
船上の過酷な労働環境に耐えなければならない
Because basically Taiwan's research ships are too sought-after
基本的に台湾の調査船は人気がありすぎるからです
So we generally have to follow the general
したがって、一般的には次の一般的なルールに従う必要があります。
do ocean these
これらを海洋で行います
When researchers go to compete this ship schedule
研究者がこの船のスケジュールを競うとき
actually quite difficult
実際にはかなり難しい
In the end we all chose fishing boats
結局みんな漁船を選びました
There are many bugs on the fishing boat
漁船には虫がたくさんいる
So our colleagues often come back after
そのため、私たちの同僚はその後戻ってくることがよくあります。
Usually his feet are covered with red bean ice
普段は足下に小豆氷が敷き詰められている
or lack of sleep
または睡眠不足
It's actually a hard job
実は大変な仕事なんです
what they did in the past
彼らが過去に何をしたのか
Nearly five years of research
5年近い研究期間
It is not easy to finally have a comparison point
最終的に視点を得るのは簡単ではない
is now everyone sees this
今では誰もがこれを見ています
white this arrow
この矢印は白です
It is this station exercise input field
当駅演習入力欄です
Although it is only a station
たかが駅なのに
but we for
しかし、私たちは
Collecting information on this site took a lot of effort
このサイトの情報を収集するにはかなりの精神力が必要でした
Then we have another observatory that is
それからもう一つの天文台があります。
This place closer to the trench
この場所は塹壕に近い
Then of course we do this research to see
それからもちろん、私たちは次のことを確認するためにこの調査を行います
close to the trench
塹壕の近く
This fault is continuously creeping
この断層は継続的に忍び寄っている
or is it locked
それともロックされていますか
if it keeps creeping
それが忍び寄るなら
that of course that is a good thing
それはもちろん良いことだということ
That is, its energy is continuously released
つまり、そのエネルギーは継続的に放出されます
but if it is locked
しかしロックされている場合
still really
本当に
some major settings
いくつかの主要な設定
in fact it is
実際それは
Can it be placed on the east coast
東海岸にも置けますか
Actually there are some
実際にはいくつかあります
some space to consider
考慮すべき余地
Besides that we also
それに加えて私たちも
The earth is like me, I also want to say
地球も私と同じだと私も言いたい
Set up the pressure level of this seabed
この海底の圧力レベルを設定します
Then this is the same as the seabed survey just now
それでは、これは先ほどの海底調査と同じです。
are complementary
補完的です
Because if the seabed is measured vigorously,
だって、海底を勢いよく測ってみたら、
when you have to observe
観察しなければならないとき
will have information
情報があるだろう
If the seabed pressure level
海底の圧力レベルが
itself is recyclable
それ自体はリサイクル可能です
I can leave it for half a year
半年くらい放置できるよ
Then I have the data for half a year
半年分のデータはあるよ
Then go and observe this
それなら行ってこれを観察してください
deformation on the seabed
海底の変形
The principle of it is actually very simple
その原理は実はとてもシンプルです
it is in fact
それは実際にあります
measure the water
水を測る
Because if the seabed deforms
海底が変形すると
Then the depth of the sea water measured by this instrument will change.
すると、この機器で計測する海水の深さが変化します。
Then what
じゃあ何
The pressure of the cold test will change
コールドテストの圧力が変化します
With this pressure difference, we can convert the deformation of Haishuang
この圧力差により、海双の変形を変換できます。
for example this
たとえばこれ
Let this line be the position before deformation, the position of Haishuang before deformation
この線を変形前の位置、変形前の海双の位置とする
Green is the deformed position
緑色は変形した位置です
Then I can see the pressure difference before deformation and the pressure difference after deformation
すると、変形前の圧力差と変形後の圧力差がわかります。
Then guess how big the vertical deformation of this sea frost is
次に、この海霜の垂直方向の変形がどのくらいの大きさであるかを推測してください。
That's usually 100 Pascale 100% change
これは通常 100 パスカルで 100% 変化します
Like a deformation of about 1 cm
1cmくらい変形したような感じ
So this instrument is very precise
したがって、この機器は非常に正確です
Then we hope that in the future we can cross the Ryukyu Trench to set up these instruments
そして、将来的には琉球海溝を越えてこれらの機器を設置できることを願っています。
Then go to see some deformation behaviors near the Ryukyu Trench
次に、琉球海溝付近の変形現象を見に行きます。
OK, let's wrap things up a little bit.
さて、話を少しまとめましょう。
Today we introduced several different methods to observe the deformation of the screen strip
今日は、スクリーンストリップの変形を観察するためのいくつかの異なる方法を紹介しました。
For example, there is this land
たとえばこんな土地があります
GNSS
GNSS
Synthetic Aperture Interferometric Radar
合成開口干渉レーダー
There's also a large ocean basin survey and a seabed piezometer.
大規模な海洋盆地の調査や海底ピエゾメーターもあります。
We can go and observe the displacement of the surface
表面の変位を観察しに行くことができます
Estimation of the fault's Chinese tree rate
断層の中国樹率の推定
and assess its potential future earthquake location
将来の地震の可能性のある場所を評価します
with the scale
スケールで
If we want to know more distant events
もっと遠い出来事を知りたければ
we can use sea connection
海のつながりを利用できます
Or use the depth of the coral reef
あるいはサンゴ礁の深さを利用する
to see these older earthquake events
これらの古い地震イベントを見るために
tsunami words
津波の言葉
We can go to see the tsunami's results
津波の結果を見に行くことができます
or a large boulder on the coast
または海岸にある大きな岩
Or look up some historical literature records
または、歴史的な文献の記録を調べてください
To guess where the tsunami might occur
津波が発生する可能性のある場所を推測するには
The source of its corresponding tsunami
対応する津波の発生源
Or the relationship with the earthquake on the screen
あるいは画面上の地震との関係
We also introduce
もご紹介します
The way the screen strips the crust deforms
スクリーンがクラストを剥がす様子が変形する
During the block screen process
ブロック画面プロセス中
before the earthquake
地震の前に
The upper plate will slowly arch
上部プレートがゆっくりとアーチ状になります
then move to land
それから陸地に移動します
then after the earthquake
それから地震の後
it will generate dive
ダイブを生成します
Then move towards the sea
それから海に向かって移動します
Then we introduce
それではご紹介します
That is, Huayi will be distributed everywhere on the fault
つまり、Huayi は断層上のあらゆる場所に分布することになります。
before the earthquake
地震の前に
Energy slowly in the depths of the fault
エネルギーは断層の深さにゆっくりと存在する
accumulate slowly
ゆっくりと蓄積する
Then this may take hundreds to thousands of years
そうなると、これには数百年から数千年かかるかもしれません
But when the earthquake happened
しかし、地震が起こったとき、
maybe 20 seconds to 30 seconds
20秒から30秒くらいかな
It can accumulate the past from hundreds to thousands of years
数百年から数千年にわたる過去を蓄積できる
These energies are released
これらのエネルギーが解放されます
Therefore, there will be a large
したがって、大きな
Rule shifts on these surfaces
これらのサーフェスでのルールの変更
If after the earthquake
地震の後だったら
In some places the energy has not been fully released
場所によってはエネルギーが完全に放出されていない
then after the earthquake
それから地震の後
It will last this Huayi
この華夷は続くだろう
Then our Taiwan is now located in this place
そして私たちの台湾は今この場所にあります
So let's study these screen strips now
それでは、これらのスクリーン ストリップを見てみましょう
is actually very important
実はとても重要です
because the screen has words
画面に文字があるから
For example, we study the Malayan Trench
たとえば、私たちはマレー海溝を研究しています。
Then this is different from the Ryukyu Trench
じゃあここは琉球海溝とは違うのか
Because if the Ryukyu Trench ruptures,
だって、もし琉球海溝が決壊したら、
Its main energy is to
その主なエネルギーは、
The direction of the Pacific
太平洋の方向
but if
しかし、もし
If a rupture occurs in the Mara Trench
マラ海溝に亀裂が発生した場合
It actually goes to the South China Sea
実は南シナ海まで行っている
Spread it to mainland China and the Indochina Peninsula
中国本土やインドシナ半島にも広がる
So it's pretty obvious that it could actually be a disaster.
したがって、それが実際に災害となる可能性があることは明らかです。
So we are in Taiwan
それで私たちは台湾にいます
We near do these implicit bands with these observations
これらの観察により、これらの暗黙のバンドがほぼ達成されます。
In fact, these experiences we can all
実際、これらの経験は私たち全員が行うことができます
pass to these Southeast Asian countries
これらの東南アジア諸国に渡します
then if we are here
それで私たちがここにいるなら
There are some better monitoring
より良いモニタリングがいくつかあります
Assessment of Earthquake Hazards for the Whole Region
地域全体の地震危険度評価
In fact, it has a considerable contribution to prevention.
実は、予防に大きく貢献しているのです。
In addition, we actually
さらに、私たちは実際に
Attached to many of these in Taiwan
台湾ではこれらの多くに取り付けられています
Mimi Mama's GPS Observation Station
ミミママのGPS観測所
Besides these observatories are used to do these
さらに、これらの天文台は次のことを行うために使用されます
scientific research
科学研究
Earthquakes used to study the silent zone
サイレントゾーンの研究に使用される地震
In fact, it has a lot of added value
実は付加価値がたくさんあるんです
For example, we actually
たとえば、私たちは実際に
These GPS Observation Stations in Taiwan
台湾のGPS観測所はこちら
we can study some
私たちはいくつか勉強することができます
The movement of these landslides in Taiwan
台湾における土砂崩れの動き
For example, this is near Mount Lu
たとえば、これは廬山の近くです
Some GPS time series we set up
セットアップしたいくつかの GPS 時系列
Coordinates change over time
時間の経過とともに座標が変化する
This is from 2005 to 2014
これは2005年から2014年までです
basic data
基礎造資料
This is the east-west and vertical components of the north-south component
これは南北成分の東西成分と垂直成分です
we can see
見える
when it rains heavily
激しい雨が降ったとき
The process of slope rising into landslide sliding
斜面の隆起から地滑りに至る過程
We want to use this information
この情報を活用したい
To learn about the mechanism of these landslides
地滑りのメカニズムを知るために
Is there any relationship between landslide sliding speed and rainfall?
土砂崩れの速度と降雨量には関係があるのでしょうか？
Are there any signs before the landslide slides?
土砂崩れの前兆はあるのか？
These can be observed from the surface
これらは表面からも観察できます
do some inversion
何らかの逆転をする
To understand the physical properties of landslide sliding surfaces
地すべり滑り面の物性を理解する
Also see
こちらもご覧ください
In fact, there are places in the landslide area that will still rise
実は土砂崩れ地域にはまだ盛り上がる場所もある
Let's say it's a slope
坂道だとしましょう
In fact you can see
実際に見ることができます
What you see is that it's an upward movement
上向きの動きであることがわかります
everyone will feel
誰もが感じるだろう
Why Landslides Shouldn't Be
なぜ地滑りがあってはいけないのか
everything slides down
すべてが滑り落ちてしまう
why is it elevated
なぜ上がっているのか
Mainly it is at the stop of landslides
主に土砂崩れの止まり場所です
So it's a relatively quiet area
比較的静かなエリアですので、
So this place is a rising
つまり、この場所は上昇しているのです
a deformation
変形
So in fact if we can have some dense observations
実際、密度の高い観察ができれば
We can also generate landslides or dive into landslides
地滑りを発生させたり、地滑りに飛び込むこともできます
There are some nice constraints
素敵な制約がいくつかあります
What are the benefits of the geophysical method?
地球物理学的手法の利点は何ですか?
Mainly because of the geophysical method
主に地球物理学的手法によるもの
Our instruments are placed in the submerged or above the surface
当社の機器は水中または水面上に設置されます
When traditional civil engineering is doing landslide monitoring
従来の土木工学が地滑り監視を行う場合
they have to specialize
彼らは専門化する必要がある
Then go set up the inclinometer
次に、傾斜計をセットアップします
But everyone can know that
でもそれは誰でもわかる
if in a very active place
非常にアクティブな場所にいる場合
that landslide
あの地滑り
landslide transport it is the effect of gravity
地滑り輸送、それは重力の影響です
So it's always slipping
だからいつも滑ってるんだよ
then you can think of
それからあなたは考えることができます
If that it places everything after that hole is cut
その穴がカットされた後にすべてを配置する場合
In fact it would have to make a new hole
実際には新たに穴を開ける必要があります
So now a one-meter brick neck costs about 8,000 yuan
現在、1メートルのレンガネックの価格は約8,000元です
as you can imagine
あなたが想像できるように
The entire hillside must be moved up
丘の斜面全体を上に移動する必要がある
For example, spending 200 million to 300 million yuan in Lisanping
例えば、梨三平で2億～3億元を使う。
Then whole the slope
それから坂全体を
But because this slope is very active
でもこの坂はとても活発なので
Then this is a decorative instrument
それからこれは装飾的な楽器です
It's all unusable now
今は全部使えなくなってしまった
Then if using this geophysical method
この地球物理学的手法を使用すると、
The way we use these observations is in fact
これらの観察結果を実際に使用する方法は次のとおりです。
we can
我々はできる
Can be detected by non-destructive methods
非破壊的な方法で検出可能
Whether it's diving, it's scattered movement
ダイビングでも、バラバラな動きでも
or these activities at the deep end
またはディープエンドでのこれらのアクティビティ
can do it all
全部できる
Alternatively, we can also
あるいは、次のこともできます。
Do some assessment of water resources
水資源の評価を行う
For example we see
たとえば、
We have some consecutive
いくつかの連続したものがあります
These GPS stations
これらの GPS ステーション
Then we can see
そうすればわかります
For example, in the vertical
例: 垂直方向
it has some obvious
それは明らかなことがあります
agglomeration of changes
変更の集合体
it goes up and down
それは上がったり下がったりします
It Long term will have a coupon
長期はクーポンあります
It's about, maybe about the Tectonic
それはおそらく地殻変動についてです
But there will be some fluctuations in its build-up
ただし、その集計には多少の変動があるでしょう
those fluctuations
それらの変動
It's actually the groundwater below.
実は地下水なんです。
Or it is related to the amount of cold water in the soil
または土壌中の冷水の量に関係します
Then we can actually use
その後、実際に使用できるようになります
It's our GPS
それは私たちのGPSです
into these collective governments
これらの集団政府に
to calculate in these soils
これらの土壌で計算するには
amount of cold water
冷水の量
Then for this entire
次に、この全体について
Regional Water Resources Assessment
地域の水資源評価
actually helps
実際には少し役立ちます
the last one is
最後のものは
We do a lot of work in travel
私たちは旅行関連で多くの仕事をしています
This is our trip to send in 2009
2009年に送る旅です
Then when we went over there to set up the station
それから私たちがステーションを設置するためにそこに行ったとき
this is an elementary school
ここは小学校です
everyone is very very nice
みんなとてもとても素敵です
why we do this
なぜこれを行うのか
So we are laying out while
それで、私たちはレイアウトしています
Also explain to these children
この子たちにも説明してください
The purpose of our observation
私たちの観察の目的
so this is actually quite interesting
これは実際には非常に興味深いです
we are there
私たちはそこにいる
Tell them about our work
私たちの仕事について彼らに伝えてください
And then use it to nurture their next generation
そしてそれを次世代の育成に活用します
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Okay, thank you very much, Dr. Hsu
はい、ありがとうございます、スー博士
give us a very good speech
とても良いスピーチをしてください
the rest of our time now
今の残りの時間
open to audience questions
聴衆の質問を受け付けます
About the content of the speech
講演内容について
Which point would I like to have a deeper understanding of
どの点をより深く理解したいですか
Or think of some good suggestions
あるいは、何か良い提案を考えてみましょう
or a problem
または問題
Please ask questions
質問してください
Thanks
ありがとう
I won't talk about big questions, please actively raise them
大きな質問については話さないので、積極的に質問してください
What about our sponsor today?
今日のスポンサーはどうですか？
Prepared some products
いくつかの商品を用意しました
he now we have
彼は今私たちにいます
October of this year
今年の10月
The two staff members of Scientist held him up
Scientist の 2 人のスタッフが彼を抱き上げた
do we have 6 or 7
6つか7つありますか
We can give it to the audience friends who asked questions in front of the head
目の前で質問してくれた観客の友達にプレゼントできます
we ask everyone to raise their hands right now
今すぐ全員に手を挙げてください
there's a microphone in front of you
あなたの目の前にマイクがあります
so there's a switch that's the green switch
緑色のスイッチがあります
so when you can speak into the microphone
マイクに向かって話せたら
Is there anyone who wants to start
始めたい人はいますか
good lady
良い女性
ask the professor
教授に聞く
We seem to be the one in the reputation zone
私たちは評判ゾーンにいるようです
101 belongs to the earthquake zone, right?
101は地震帯に属しますよね？
that said besides saying
それは言うだけでなく言った
Is there anything beyond our possible detection
私たちの検出可能な範囲を超えるものはありますか
prevent it from happening to him thank you
彼にそれが起こらないようにしてください、ありがとう
So we know that means
つまり、それが意味することはわかります
If we're on the new TV if we make some
もし私たちが新しいテレビを見ているなら、何かを作ったら
After water injection, it will cause some local changes in India
注水後、インドの局所的な変化が起こるだろう
Will change the situation in the local Indy
地元インディの状況を変えるだろう
then maybe
それなら多分
is to make the earthquake happen earlier or later
地震を早めるか遅らせるかです
but now what i think
でも今私が思うこと
It should be difficult to artificially
人為的に作るのは難しいはず
do some action
何らかの行動を起こす
so that this earthquake does not happen
この地震が起こらないように
Yes it is more difficult
はい、それはもっと難しいです
It would be better to find a way to take care of the house.
家の世話をする方法を見つけた方が良いでしょう。
This is actually in Canada they
ここは実際にはカナダにあります
In western Canada they actually have a lot of oil and gas development
カナダ西部では実際に多くの石油とガスの開発が行われています
that's or something they'll pick
それか彼らが選ぶもの
They use some drip heat and he might have to pour water into it
点滴熱を使用するので、水を注ぐ必要があるかもしれません
Then they found that when the water is injected, it will lead to life, that is, it will cause a lot of small droplet vibrations
すると彼らは、水を注入すると生命が生まれる、つまり小さな水滴の振動がたくさん起こることを発見しました。
What about these small droplet shocks, for some, are
一部の人にとって、このような小さな飛沫による衝撃はどうでしょうか。
He might just be an energy release character
彼はただのエネルギー放出キャラクターかもしれません
But it's also possible that he'll make some of the fault zone's drip quake
しかし、彼が断層帯のドリップ地震を起こす可能性もある
It couldn't have happened so soon, it happened earlier
そんなに早く起こるはずはなかった、もっと早くに起こった
So now when you intervene, some will be good and some will be bad
だから今、あなたが介入すると、良いものもあれば悪いものもあるでしょう
It's hard for you to go because we don't know now
今は分からないので、行くのは難しいです
fault his own coin is in what state
自分のコインはどのような状態になっているのでしょうか
So you don't know if you're good or bad for the area after you do this movement
つまり、この運動をした後は、自分がその地域にとって良いことなのか悪いことなのかわかりません。
Yes, because some of them may have already crossed the boundary
はい、すでに境界を越えている人もいるかもしれないので
All you need is a small trace, some changes in coins
必要なのは、小さなトレースとコインの小銭だけです
You'll make him have a big tick
あなたは彼を大興奮させるでしょう
some if it's still far away, you might do something
まだ遠いなら、何かしてくれるかもしれない
won't let him, just no, in fact he won't have any changes
許しません、ただ、いいえ、実際には彼には何の変化もありません
So this is actually because seismologists or earth dancers
つまり、これは実際には地震学者またはアースダンサーによるものです
Now the biggest one, the problem is
さて、最大の問題、問題は
for faulting his coin
彼のコインに欠陥があるため
In fact, we don't know the state of India on the fault.
実際のところ、断層に関するインドの状況はわかりません。
All we know is that the earthquake happened and India will change
私たちが知っているのは、地震が起こり、インドは変わるということだけです
But we don't know what its Indian state was in its original state
しかし、そのインドの元の状態がどのようなものだったのかはわかりません。
Because the recovery period of the earthquake is very long
地震の復興期間が非常に長いため
So we say that we need to understand the process of an earthquake
したがって、地震のプロセスを理解する必要があると言います。
In fact, only from the past 100 years or the last 20 or 30 years
実際には、過去 100 年か、過去 20 ～ 30 年間のことだけです。
this is insufficient
これでは不十分です
right
右
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
So it's still unknown
なのでまだ不明です
quite difficult for the present
現状ではかなり難しい
right
右
Thanks
ありがとう
well the lady is behind
まあ、女性は後ろにいる
i want to ask
聞きたいです
I was just curious
ちょっと気になっただけ
Just got the orange one that can measure pressure
圧力を測定できるオレンジ色のものを入手しました
The one you said can only be used once
あなたが言ったものは一度しか使えません
Then I want to ask how long it can last
じゃあどれくらい続くのか聞きたい
In addition, on that land, measurement is prediction
またその土地では、計測は予測である
It is the part to measure the possible slippage of the earthquake
地震時の滑りを計測する部品です
That's because the geology of each place is different
それは場所ごとに地質が違うからです
that includes it underground possibly
おそらく地下も含まれます
there may be some that flow by themselves
自動的に流れるものもあるかもしれません
For example, groundwater or some
たとえば、地下水など
It's like comparing minerals, fluid minerals, etc.
鉱物、液体鉱物などを比較するようなものです。
Will it be like this
こうなるのかな
Would it interfere with you measuring that
それを測定するのに邪魔になりますか
just maybe it's slipping on the plate
皿の上で滑ってるだけかもしれない
Or something related to earthquake prediction
あるいは地震予知に関するもの
Thanks
ありがとう
The instrument just mentioned
先ほど挙げた楽器
That one-time instrument is dependent on the battery
使い捨ての機器はバッテリーに依存します
how long the battery lasts
バッテリーがどのくらい持続するか
if we have a good battery
良いバッテリーがあれば
it can last five to ten years
それは5年から10年続く可能性があります
right
右
But if, for example, the instrument
しかし、たとえば楽器の場合、
Sometimes there are problems because
時々問題が発生することがありますので、
when we set up
私たちがセットアップするとき
maybe some sea breakers
もしかしたら海上ブレーカーもいるかもしれない
it sometimes buries that instrument
それは時々その楽器を埋める
Then let's send the deep wave signal
それではディープウェーブ信号を送信しましょう
when it's time to wake up to work
起きて仕事をする時間になったら
maybe there is no way
たぶん方法はありません
We will just because if it is buried after
後で埋もれる場合はそうするだけです
it may be difficult
難しいかもしれない
That instrument may not be useful
その楽器は役に立たないかもしれない
Because there are actually some
実際に海底にもあるので
some subsea avalanches
いくつかの海底雪崩
Then if we don't when it's time to deploy
デプロイ時期になってもそうしないと
Maybe the position of the one-flag spin is not good enough
ワンフラッグスピンの位置が良くないのかもしれない
there will be such a situation
そのような状況があるでしょう
Basically its life is related to the battery
基本的に寿命はバッテリーに関係します
If we can buy a good battery
良いバッテリーを買えたら
Basically it can last five to ten years
基本的には5年から10年は持ちます
Another question is that
もう一つの質問は、
If some of the signals we see are related to groundwater
私たちが目にする信号の一部が地下水に関連している場合
Could it be related to the news-making of these environments?
これらの環境がニュースになることと関係があるのでしょうか?
indeed it will
確かにそうなります
How do we distinguish
ではどうやって区別するのか
That is to say, it is related to the environment
つまり、環境と関係があるということです。
or we measured these terranes
あるいは、これらの地形を測定しました
Signals of activity on these faults
これらの断層での活動の兆候
the first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
when we have this doubt
私たちがこの疑問を抱いたとき
we will collect
私たちは集めます
That place, for example, water level data, gas tank data
その場所、例えば水位データ、ガソリンタンクデータ
Then do the comparison
それから比較してみます
and then go and take all of these neighbors
それから近所の人たち全員を連れて行ってください
The behavior of the test stations is used for comparison
テストステーションの動作は比較に使用されます
look it is very
見てください、とてもそうです
Local refers to the local behavior or the behavior of a large area
ローカルとは、ローカルな動作または広いエリアの動作を指します。
Then we can clarify
そうすれば明確にできます
this behavior is
この行動は
more local or regional
よりローカルまたは地域的な
Then it may have something to do with the environment
それなら環境も関係あるかもしれない
But this requires dissection
しかし、これには解剖が必要です
and you need to collect a lot of different data
さまざまなデータを収集する必要があります
That is indeed the data
まさにそのデータです
If it were possible for observers on the surface to record these inquiries about these environments
もし地表の観察者がこれらの環境に関するこれらの問い合わせを記録することができたら
Excuse me Dr. Xu
すみません、徐先生。
Which areas around Taipei are areas with fault zones?
台北周辺で断層帯がある地域はどこですか?
Now, what kind of monitoring is the government doing?
さて、政府はどのような監視を行っているのでしょうか？
and some information to inform the public
そして一般向けの情報
Thanks
ありがとう
In fact, the main active fault in Taiwan
実は台湾の主な活断層は、
In fact, the Geographical Information Survey Institute has declassified
実際、国土地理院は機密を解除しました。
It has different active faults and different levels
さまざまな活断層とさまざまなレベルがある
Then each has a different definition
そうすると、それぞれ定義が異なります
Well, there are actually some monitors on these faults.
そうですね、実際にはこれらの障害を監視するモニターがいくつかあります。
There is regular monitoring data
定期的なモニタリングデータがある
like some of these gps jean is
これらのGPSジーンズのいくつかのように
Why is his job continuous Zhan is to monitor
ザンが監視する仕事が継続しているのはなぜですか
It is to continuously monitor the deformation of these surfaces.
これらの表面の変形を継続的に監視することです。
But now the difficulty is to say that the fault precedes the activity
しかし、ここで問題となるのは、障害が活動に先行していると言えることです。
Everyone pays attention to the front move phenomenon on him.
誰もが彼の前方移動現象に注目しています。
But the former move is actually very concerned in the world at present
しかし、前者の動きは、現在世界では実際に非常に懸念されています
It is the observation of the frontlight phenomenon of earthquakes
地震の順光現象の観測です
In fact, there has been no major breakthrough
実際には大きな進歩はなかった
because of the considerable difficulty
かなりの困難があるため
So while we monitor
それで、私たちが監視している間、
But we do monitor the data
しかし、私たちはデータを監視しています
it can tell you
それはあなたに伝えることができます
Areas of possible future rupture
将来的に破裂する可能性のある領域
probably somewhere
おそらくどこかで
But it is difficult for us to tell you exactly
しかし、私たちにとって正確にお伝えすることは困難です
what time is it going to happen
何時に起こりますか
it's more difficult
それはもっと難しいです
there are three here
ここに3つあります
this way first
まずはこちらへ
Dr. Hsu, thank you for talking about this
シュー博士、この件について話してくれてありがとう
let us know something
何か知らせてください
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
can you add some
いくつか追加していただけますか
Which legends are more scientifically based?
どの伝説がより科学的に基づいていますか?
For example, the appearance of Emperor Yu represents the occurrence of an earthquake.
例えば、禹帝の出現は地震の発生を表します。
Or biological changes
あるいは生物学的な変化
Or something that has no scientific basis
あるいは科学的根拠のないもの
Let us in our ordinary life
普段の生活の中でいきましょう
There is also some will to judge
判断する意志もある
At noon they are for creatures when the earthquake comes
正午、地震が来ると生き物たちのために
they did a lot of research
彼らはたくさんの研究をしました
My own reaction to this creature actually
この生き物に対する私自身の反応
because if you want to include these as earthquake precursors
これらを地震前兆として含めたい場合は
That's every time these animals have these reactions
これらの動物がこのような反応をするときはいつもそうなります
you will have an earthquake
地震が起こるでしょう
right
右
If we only look at the earthquake precursors now, then we can say in hindsight
今、地震の前兆だけを見てみると、後から考えると次のように言えます。
Our cat didn't sleep before this earthquake or something
うちの猫はこの地震か何かの前には寝なかった
so it's kind of like
だからそれは一種のようなものです
It's because you're an afterthought
それはあなたが後付けだからです
If we really want to study precursors we have to be
本当に前駆体を研究したいのであれば、そうしなければなりません
what is the normal behavior of this animal
この動物の通常の行動は何ですか
That is, he can correspond to an earthquake every time there is an abnormality
つまり、異常が発生するたびに地震に対応できるということです。
But if this cannot be established
しかし、これが確立できない場合は、
It's hard for you to convince others to say
他人にそう言って説得するのは難しい
my creature
私の生き物
This starts with some behaviors of some animals
これはいくつかの動物の行動から始まります
can be used to predict earthquakes
地震の予知に使用できる
right
右
so
それで
Some can, some can't, probably not
できる人もいるし、できない人もいるし、おそらくできない人もいる
right
右
it's hard to be sure
それを確信するのは難しい
Because this is not the same as forecasting weather
天気予報とは違うので
Actually something is different
実は何かが違う
Because if the earthquake is predicted
だって地震が予言されたら
If you keep saying the earthquake is coming
地震が来ると言い続けたら
earthquake is coming
地震が来る
You didn't even come
あなたも来なかった
The next time you say an earthquake is coming
次に地震が来ると言ったら
everyone stop running
みんな走るのやめて
OK
OK
At this time, if an earthquake strikes
この時、地震が起きたら
it will be very serious
それはとても深刻なことになるだろう
So if your climate forecast is inaccurate
したがって、気候予測が不正確であれば、
That's actually
それは実際に
The consequences would be less severe
結果はそれほど深刻ではないでしょう
Compared with earthquake prediction
地震予知との比較
So earthquake prediction actually has
つまり、地震予知は実際にあるのです
quite a long way to go
かなり長い道のり
ok get ready
はい、準備してください
hello please ask
こんにちは、聞いてください
that volcano erupted
その火山が噴火した
Will it drive that fault zone to rupture?
その断層帯が破壊されることになるのでしょうか？
Is there a causal relationship between them?
それらの間に因果関係はあるのでしょうか？
like that
そのように
Kameyama is old and quite close to the Ryukyu Trench
亀山は古く、琉球海溝にかなり近い
For example, the Tatun Volcanic Society
たとえば、大屯火山協会
next to it is the one
その隣にあるのは
Mountain Foot Fault
ベータフットフォルト
Is there any kind of
何かありますか？
cause and effect thank you
因果応報、ありがとう
it is indeed possible
それは確かに可能です
because like
なぜなら、好きだから
2016 Yumoto Earthquake, Japan
2016年日本雄本地震
it is it yumoto earthquake
それは湯本地震です
that earthquake
あの地震
It actually happened on the south side of Aso Volcano
阿蘇火山の南側で実際に起きた事件
But after that earthquake
でも、あの地震の後、
Volcanoes have some relatively violent activities
火山には比較的激しい活動があります
On the contrary
それどころか
Because you just have some movement of these earthquakes or volcanoes
なぜなら、これらの地震や火山の動きがあるだけだからです
It will cause changes in Indonesia in that area
その分野でインドネシアに変化をもたらすだろう
That does have the potential to trigger activity on nearby faults.
これにより、近くの断層で活動が引き起こされる可能性があります。
there is this possibility
この可能性はあります
the student
学生
The student I want to consult is my first department
私が相談したい学生は私の最初の学部です
Then I noticed that some instruments introduced just now are
すると、今紹介した楽器の中には、
put it over there
そこに置いてください
and maybe a year later
そしておそらく1年後
Look at the data it collects
収集したデータを見てください
what i want to ask is
そこで私が聞きたいのは、
Earthquake early warning systems are now available at
緊急地震速報システムは以下で利用可能になりました。
after the earthquake has occurred
地震が起こった後
Send alerts to people's mobile phones
人々の携帯電話にアラートを送信する
Then I want to ask if there is any instrument
それで何か楽器があるか聞きたいのですが
continuous monitoring
継続的な監視
Then minutes before a possible earthquake,
そして、地震の可能性がある数分前に、
forecast
予報
this may be difficult
これは難しいかもしれない
just with everyone
ただみんなと一緒に
I just told you the same
先ほども同じことを言いました
that is
あれは
Because what kind of so-called precursor phenomenon will occur before the earthquake
というのは、地震の前にどのようないわゆる前兆現象が起こるのか。
Because we don't see many such cases now
今ではそのようなケースはあまり見られないので、
Presumably there are successful predictions in the literature
おそらく文献には成功した予測があるでしょう
That is, there was a successful early warning before the earthquake.
つまり、地震の前に早期警戒が成功したということだ。
Actually Haicheng Earthquake
実は海城地震
It should be that the Haicheng earthquake in 1976 was successful
1976年の海城地震は成功したはずだ
All other earthquakes are not recognized by scientists
他のすべての地震は科学者によって認識されていません
was successful
成功した
so honestly
正直に言うと
What to do before an earthquake
地震の前にやるべきこと
Actually we don't know
実際のところは分かりません
Again because of this relationship
またこの関係だから
So it is difficult for you to say that before the earthquake
地震前はそんなこと言いにくいんですね
Hurry up and tell everyone that an earthquake is about to happen
急いでみんなに地震が起きると伝えてください
Actually it's quite difficult
実はかなり難しいんです
Earthquake warning means
地震警報の意味
If your earthquake is far away from you
地震が遠く離れている場合
that it happened now
それが今起こったこと
Because it takes a while for the wave to reach you
波が届くまでに時間がかかるから
so if you get farther away from you
だからあなたから遠ざかると
You'll have more time to make early warnings
早期に警告を発する時間が増えます
like a tsunami
津波のように
Because the tsunami propagation speed may be hundreds of kilometers per hour
津波の伝播速度は時速数百キロメートルにも達する可能性があるため
So if you compare earthquakes that occur farther away
では、より遠くで発生する地震を比較してみると、
you know it happened
それが起こったことを知っていますか
That's because the wave spread to Taiwan may be
台湾にもその波が波及する可能性があるからです。
It takes a while, then you may have tens of seconds and minutes
しばらく時間がかかりますが、その後は数十秒、数分かかる場合があります
or have an hour left to do these preparations
または、これらの準備をするために 1 時間残っています
But what if it happened near Taiwan?
しかし、それが台湾の近くで起こったらどうなるでしょうか？
In fact, because it waves the boat because the distance is very close
実は距離が近いので船を振ってしまうので
So you soon this burrow will come
だから、すぐにこの巣穴が来るでしょう
You might be too late to run, right?
走るには遅すぎるかも知れませんね？
It was just said that one was admitted to predict success
成功を予測することが認められたと言われました
Then why was that scene predictable?
では、なぜあのシーンは予想できたのでしょうか？
because its symptoms are obvious, yes
その兆候は明らかだから、はい
What are the signs?
兆候は何ですか?
it was just before the earthquake
それは地震の直前でした
it has some noticeable deformation
目立つ変形があります
Crustal deformation, they did some leveling
地殻変動、彼らはある程度の平準化を行った
For vertical traces of two layers of earth
2層の土の垂直トレース用
it found some obvious changes
明らかな変化がいくつか見つかりました
And before the earthquake
そして地震の前に
it has foreshocks it has dense foreshocks
前震があります 密度の高い前震があります
There are dense earthquakes, small earthquakes, yes
密集した地震もあれば、小さな地震もある、はい
Then this is the beginning, the warning
それから、これが始まりです、警告です
Yes please evacuate
はい、避難してください
That earthquake was a success, yes
あの地震は成功したよ、はい
But the long mountain in the back is right behind
でも後ろの長い山はすぐ後ろにある
Also nearby. That one didn't work out.
近くにもありました。あれはうまくいきませんでした。
right
右
so
それで
Controversy is still quite big
論争はまだかなり大きい
ok sir
わかりました、先生
I want to ask Dr. Xu about the recent neutral blog
最近の中立的なブログについて徐博士に聞きたいです
Neutral betting is gravitational betting
ニュートラルベッティングは重力ベッティングです
get the nobel prize
ノーベル賞をもらう
I've seen this before
これは前にも見たことがある
Earth's electric plane may be
地球の電気飛行機は、
predict
予測する
like this last generation
この最後の世代のように
this possibility
この可能性
Does Professor Xu have any information on this?
Xu教授はこれについて何か情報を持っていますか？
About our power layer
パワーレイヤーについて
The onboard power layer is predictable
オンボードの電源プレーンは予測可能です
our earthquake
私たちの地震
Well, yesterday I saw a message saying
さて、昨日私は次のようなメッセージを見ました
This golden heel on earth
この地上の黄金のかかと
radiation of copper
銅的輻射性
when the volcano erupts
火山が噴火するとき
Might be able to see that radiation beneath us
私たちの下にある放射線が見えるかもしれない
that radiation
那個輻射線
that creates the geographic layer
地理レイヤーを作成する
electric wire
電線
The atmosphere, the electrotransfer layer, should have followed the atmosphere
大気層、電子転写層の後に大気層を設ける必要があります。
These changes are important for us to predict earthquakes
これらの変化は地震を予測する上で重要です
Is there any current scientific evidence
現在の科学的証拠はありますか
For the electrotransfer layer
電子転写層用
An old hole created by an earthquake in the electrotransfer layer
地震により電子転写層に生じた古い穴
Indeed, some can be observed online
実際、一部はオンラインで観察できます
But just like I said earlier
しかし、先ほども言ったように
In fact such an old hole line like this
実はこんな古い穴のラインが
It happens even when there are no earthquakes
地震がなくても起こる
becomes saying that if we really want to use this
本当にこれを使用したい場合は、
Help come and go to understand the pre-creation of earthquakes
地震が起こる前を理解するために行き来するのを手伝ってください
we have to explain
私たちは説明しなければなりません
What kind of abnormal phenomena
どのような異常現象なのか
Could all these anomalies lead to an earthquake?
これらすべての異常が地震を引き起こす可能性はあるでしょうか?
but if there is no
しかし、それがない場合は
how high is your accuracy
あなたの精度はどのくらいですか
For example because if you are generally right or wrong
たとえば、あなたが一般的に正しいか間違っている場合、
just a normal chance
ただの普通のチャンス
So I think your accuracy
だからあなたの正確さは
at least seventy percent
少なくとも70パーセント
It can be said that it is more feasible
より実現可能性が高いと言えます
Because you guessed it was normal
それが普通だと思っていたから
That's at least what you're going to do if you're going to use this method
このメソッドを使用する場合は、少なくともこれを実行する必要があります
Regardless of the method, when you learn about earthquake prediction
方法は問わず、地震予知を学ぶときは
So can you reach this threshold?
さて、あなたはこの閾値に到達できるでしょうか？
It's not that everyone is talking about it after the earthquake
震災後みんなが話題にしているわけではない
i see this which i see
私はこれを見ます
This becomes less scientifically based.
これは科学的根拠が薄れてしまいます。
ok here's another question
さて、別の質問です
Ask Dr. Xu
徐博士に聞く
Because I do avoidable things with my kids
避けるべきことを子供たちとやっているから
We must be very interested in observing the natural environment
私たちは自然環境を観察することに非常に興味を持っているに違いありません
A few years ago we went to the Zhenyang point of Jiufen 23
数年前、私たちは九份23の鎮陽点に行きました。
Want to see a lot of wet damage protruding from the ground
地面から突き出たウェットダメージをたくさん見たい
We don't quite understand what kind of power this is
これがどのような力なのかはよくわかりません
what kind of action
どのような行動ですか
where does its history come from
その歴史はどこから来たのか
would stick out the surface so much moisture damage
表面が突き出ると湿気によるダメージが大きくなります
Can Dr. Hsu tell us, please?
スー博士から教えていただけますか？
Wet damage Because of wet damage, it is usually when you are at noon
水濡れダメージ 水濡れダメージのため、通常お昼時となります。
And because of that low relationship
そして、その関係性が低いため、
It is the action of the water flow that creates
それは水の流れの効果によって生み出されます。
The death loss was how it was lifted up from the ground before
死の喪失は、以前に地面から持ち上げられた方法でした
Because as far as I know there shouldn't be
私の知る限りではそんなことはないはずだから
Limestone
石灰岩
So there should be no casualties.
だから死傷者は出ないはずだ。
That might not necessarily be a death loss
それは必ずしも死亡事故ではないかもしれない
For example, if you eat lightly
たとえば、軽く食べた場合
For example, if you say rock
たとえば、あなたがロックだと言うと、
If your rock composition has strong and weak
岩石の組成に強弱がある場合
That's because if it's exposed to the surface
表面に露出してしまうと
because of your rain
あなたの雨のせいで
it washes out some of the weaker rocks first
最初に弱い岩石の一部を洗い流します
the harder stuff stays there
より難しいものはそこに残ります
Then maybe it will produce a shape like this
そうすると多分こんな形になると思います
ok wait a minute
わかりました、ちょっと待ってください
Is there anything else here?
ここには他に何かありますか？
the lady
女性
Have been to the Taichung Science and Technology Museum
台中科学技術館に行ってきました
they have an address delay
アドレス遅延がある
That's because of the plate movement we've seen before
それは以前に見たプレートの動きのせいです
It's all because of Zhang Lie at the central level
すべては中央レベルの張烈のせいだ
then push the plate
それからプレートを押します
make plates collide
プレートを衝突させる
Then the ocean can be silent
そうすれば海は静かになれる
But its new saying is that
しかし、その新しい言い伝えは、
Because the plate on the edge of the plate is older
お皿の端の皿が古いので
so it cools
それで涼しくなる
It becomes denser after cooling
冷やすと密度が高くなります
so it's silent
だから静かだ
and because of its obscurity
そしてその曖昧さゆえに
Only then did he pull Zhang Lie at the central level behind him
そうして初めて、彼は中央レベルの張烈を後ろに引っ張った
Then my new way of speaking
それから私の新しい話し方
because i haven't heard of it before
今まで聞いたことがないので
In that exercise, it was talking about this
その演習では、これについて話していました
so i don't know what the doctor said about this
だから医者がこれについて何と言ったか分からない
move with the old plate
古いプレートと一緒に移動する
It was promoted by Zhang Lie at the central level
中央レベルで張烈によって推進された
plate collision
プレート衝突
Then keep quiet about which one would make more sense.
それから、どちらがより理にかなっているかについては沈黙してください。
No both exist
両方とも存在しない
Because the tiles are generated when the Central Group
タイルは中央グループのときに生成されるため、
It just pushes the oceanic plate to the side
海洋プレートを横に押すだけです
Then the final process is due to the relationship of gravity
そして最終プロセスは重力の関係によるものです
It actually brings the plates down
それは実際に皿を下げます
So both forces work
つまり両方の力が働くのです
both work
どちらも機能します
It's just that the place of action is different
活躍の場が違うだけ
But it's all driven by plate movement
しかし、それはすべてプレートの動きによって引き起こされます
both have always been
どちらもいつもそうだった
because it was emphatically saying
と強調して言っていたので
In fact, it is not the central set that pushes the plates to collide
実際、プレートを衝突させるのは中央セットではありません。
It's that the central set was pulled apart after the plates disappeared.
それは、プレートがなくなった後に中央のセットがバラバラになったことです。
It has been emphasized that the point is
要点は次のように強調されています。
Concealing first and centering pulling out later
最初に隠して後でセンタリングで引き出す
I'm not sure which of these two forces contributes more
この 2 つの力のどちらがより多く寄与しているのかわかりません
But at least all I knew was
しかし少なくとも私が知っていたのは
Both forces are plate action
どちらの力もプレート作用です
It is the driving force provided by the plate movement
プレートの動きによる駆動力です
I remember Zhang Lie very much
張烈のことをとても覚えています
that is
あれは
The implicit contribution is also
暗黙の貢献もまた、
that's right
それは正しい
it's you
それはあなたです
when the earth culverts upwards
地球が上向きに暗渠になるとき
he will put
彼は置きます
Both active and passive
アクティブにもパッシブにも
right
右
then when silent
それから黙っているとき
because of gravity
重力のせいで
he would have been down
彼は落ち込んでいただろう
so he'll pull it down
だから彼はそれを引き下げるだろう
So these two effects
つまり、この2つの効果は、
should have both
両方あるはずです
OK thank you
わかりました、ありがとう
ok there's one behind
OK、後ろに1人います
Hello Dr. Xu
こんにちは、徐博士
I'm a postdoc at that autobiographical center
私はその自伝センターの博士研究員です
He wants to consult with Dr.
彼は博士に相談したいと思っています。
just say
言うだけ
like the one just now
今のような
the one under the ground
地面の下のもの
Sensing instrument
センシング機器
is that possible
それは可能ですか
like tie a rope
ロープを結ぶように
Then
それから
wait till it's decided
決まるまで待ってください
pull it up like this
このように引き上げます
reuse
重複使用
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
And then there is that
そして、それがあります
just saw it
ちょうどそれを見た
under the sea
海中に
just dive
ただ潜る
dive down
潜る
to measure
測定する
His lower status
彼の低い地位
in this way
この上
will that be that
それはそうなるだろうか
In case of the influence of that tide
あの潮の影響なら
would be less accurate like this
このように精度は低くなります
Still flat
まだ横ばい
Rise and fall
上がり下がり
The last one is to say
最後に言うのは、
Just now the doctor announced the dynamic changes of the tsunami
たった今、医師が津波のダイナミックな変化を発表しました
Will there be a typhoon at that time?
その時は台風が来るでしょうか？
Will it have some influence on him?
それは彼に何らかの影響を与えるでしょうか？
For example, it may increase the speed of the wave boat or something.
たとえば、波のボートなどの速度を上げることができます。
Thanks
ありがとう
ok i try to remember all your questions
わかりました、あなたの質問をすべて覚えてみます
Can the first one be tied with a rope?
最初のものはロープで縛ることができますか？
of course not
もちろん違います
because i think you should be
あなたはそうあるべきだと思うから
Actually, I don't know if you have ever engaged in marine activities.
実際、マリンアクティビティをしたことがあるかどうかはわかりません。
Because our instruments are at least ten or twenty kilograms
私たちの楽器は少なくとも10キロか20キロありますので、
Then you put in the water to a depth of 2,000 meters
次に水深2,000メートルまで沈みます。
basically you can't
基本的にはできません
Because that resistance is too great
その抵抗が大きすぎるから
In fact, as long as you are about tens of meters, you are fine.
実際、数十メートルくらい離れていれば大丈夫です。
One or two hundred meters is OK
100メートルか200メートルなら大丈夫
But 4,000 meters is very difficult
でも4000メートルはかなり難しい
so it is impossible to tie the rope
だからロープを結ぶことは不可能だ
We're now actually going to have an aluminum ground setup
ここからは実際にアルミニウムの接地セットアップを行っていきます。
That means after we sink the instrument to the bottom of the ocean now
つまり、今、楽器を海の底に沈めた後
Then let's say we turn off the car
次に、車のエンジンを切ったとしましょう
Then when the time comes we'll hand it over
それでは時期が来たらお渡しします
Then it will have a
それから、それは
Ruins' device
遺跡の装置
so it will float up
だから浮き上がるだろう
And then it will flash when it comes up
そして、それが立ち上がると点滅します
then we can
それならできます
find where this instrument is
この楽器がどこにあるかを見つける
But our instruments are sometimes taken away by Yunming
でも僕らの楽器は時々ユンミンに奪われてしまうんだ
Then blackmail us like this
そして私たちをこのように脅迫します
Hehehe
ふふふ
right then
すぐに
next thing you said
次にあなたが言ったこと
Well
良い
Will it be affected by tides?
潮の影響を受けるのでしょうか？
The tide is changing because of the tide
潮のせいで潮が変わる
it is cycle
それはサイクルです
it is recoverable
それは回復可能です
That
それか
This deformation of the earth is irreversible
この地球の変形は元に戻せない
So it is easy to distinguish
なので見分けやすいです
and the tidal cycle
そして潮の満ち引き
The main cycle is 12 hours
メインサイクルは12時間
Well
良い
just uh
ただ、ああ
12 hours 20 hours
12時間 20時間
Its several Modes are
いくつかのモードは次のとおりです。
do you know how often it is
どのくらいの頻度か知っていますか
So basically you're not going to talk to the normal
基本的に普通の人と話すつもりはない
Earthquake or plate movement signal
地震またはプレートの動きの信号
is mixed together
混ざっている
because of the tide
潮のせいで
Our human study of tides
私たちの人間による潮汐研究
Scientists have thoroughly studied tides
科学者は潮汐を徹底的に研究しました
It's all these Mode it
それはすべてこれらのモードです
it has
それは持っています
how much each frequency
各周波数はどれくらいですか
have very detailed records
非常に詳細な記録がある
then you say
それからあなたは言います
when the typhoon comes
台風が来ると
if there is a tsunami
津波が来たら
Will the typhoon affect the tsunami?
台風は津波に影響しますか?
Then I want to answer yes
それなら「はい」と答えたいです
Tsunamis are very different from typhoons
津波は台風とは大きく異なります
because of the tsunami
津波のせいで
It's because of the sea worm's misalignment
シーワームのズレのせいです
so you whole sea worm
だから君は海の虫だ
The one where all of the above seawater happens
上記の海水がすべて起こる場所
are affected by fluctuations
変動の影響を受ける
But the general sea breeze
でも、全体的に海風が
It's just that the sea water is very submerged.
ただ、海水がかなり浸かっています。
you will be affected
あなたは影響を受けるでしょう
but you won't affect deep
でも深くは影響しないよ
So your typhoon is actually a comparative
つまり、あなたの台風は実際には比較可能なものです
surface movement
表面の動き
But the tsunami is a deep movement
しかし、津波は深い動きです
So why can it spread so
ではなぜこれほどまでに広まるのか
it can actually span the entire pacific
実際には太平洋全体に及ぶ可能性があります
For example, an earthquake reaching the sea of ​​South America
たとえば、南アメリカの海にまで達した地震
its tsunami could travel to japan
その津波は日本に到達する可能性がある
Is it because it is a holistic movement
全体的な動きだからでしょうか？
Then because your sea worm is comparing the ocean
それなら、あなたの海の虫が海を比較しているからです
Because the water is deeper
水深が深いので
When it reaches the land, its sea water
陸地に到達すると海水が
that sea worm will become shallow
その海のワームは浅くなるだろう
So the wave height of your tsunami will become higher
そうすればあなたの津波の波高はさらに高くなります
like a water gun
水鉄砲のように
will cause great harm
大きな害をもたらすだろう
So the typhoon should not affect
なので台風の影響は無いはずです
Trump's Slave
トランプの奴隷
good
良い
ok if there is no question i would like to ask a question
質問がなければ、質問したいと思います
you just saw taiwan
あなたは今台湾を見ました
our island
私たちの島
Lots and lots of that GPS
たくさんのGPS
How many stations are there?
駅は何駅ありますか?
Now there are more than 400
現在有400多個
400 means all of you all
400は皆さん全員を意味します
different units
異なる単位
More than 400 units put up
400以上のユニットが出品されています
Then what we have is longer
そうすれば、私たちが持っているものはもっと長いです
put it long ago
ずっと前に置いた
Some are relatively new
比較的新しいものもある
then we know that now
それなら今ならわかります
These instruments are more and more advanced
これらの機器はますます進化しています
because everyone's mobile phone
みんなの携帯電話だから
the GPS one
GPSのもの
The sensitivity is getting higher and higher
感度はどんどん上がっていきます
Then
それから
because of your measurement
あなたの測定値のせいで
you don't need to know every second
毎秒知る必要はない
You measure it about once a day
1日1回くらい測ります
calibration primary
校正一次
take one
取一個
data is enough
データで十分です
Then our current chip
次に、現在のチップ
that more and more
それはますます
It may be getting smaller and smaller
どんどん小さくなってしまうかもしれない
Power consumption is getting less and less
消費電力はどんどん少なくなっている
Then it can be released indefinitely sometimes
その後、場合によっては無期限に解放される場合があります
Needless to say, people have to peel the grass
言うまでもなく、人間は草をむかなければなりません
go find that thing
それを探しに行きます
we can know around there
私たちはそこら辺を知ることができます
Then use the side of your instrument to put that
次に、楽器の側面を使ってそれを置きます
All the signals are passed on
すべての信号が配信されます
The things in its memory can be passed here.
記憶にあるものをここに渡すことができます。
Are you going this way now?
今はこっちに行くの？
It's very convenient if you go this way
ここに行くととても便利です
unnecessary
不要
We don't need hard-working students
勤勉な学生は必要ありません
Go to every deep mountain to dig up the grass
あらゆる深い山へ草を掘りに行く
You can be within a few meters of that
あなたはそこから数メートル以内にいることができます
You can catch that signal
その信号をキャッチできます
Or let it go to the base station to go to the whole
または、基地局に送信して全体に送信します。
That is to say, we can digitize it as soon as possible.
それはできるだけ早く電子化するということです。
Then this we can go to
それから、これに行きましょう
This data will be more convenient to obtain
このデータの取得がより便利になります
Because in fact because of the mountains
だって実は山のせいで
Mountains are the worst place for communications
山はコミュニケーションにとって最悪の場所だ
Because Chunghwa Telecom is a place where people live
中華電信は人が住む場所だから
good communication quality
良好な通信品質
The situation in the mountains where no one lives is actually very bad
誰も住んでいない山の状況は実際には非常に悪いです
so
それで
Maybe in cities or major cities
おそらく都市や大都市では
Your cell phone coverage is actually pretty good
携帯電話の通信範囲は実際かなり良好です
But after going to the mountains, there are actually big problems
でも、山に行ってみると実は大きな問題があるんです
In fact, we encountered a big problem in the transmission in the mountainous area
実は山中で通信に大きな問題が発生しました
Even if we have recorded
録音したとしても
But the signal can't come out, people still have to go there
でも信号は出ない、人々はまだそこへ行かなければならない
this is a problem
これは問題だ
In addition to that
それに加えて
Because we do confidential positioning
機密ポジショニングを行っているため
then we have to know
それなら私たちは知らなければなりません
We have to have some control points on the surface
サーフェス上にいくつかのコントロール ポイントが必要です
That point cannot be moved
その点は移動できません
because what we need to know is to say
なぜなら私たちが知る必要があるのは、こう言うことだからです
Its change over time today
今日の時間の経過による変化
So if our mobile phone can be used as a Receiver
それで、私たちの携帯電話が受信機として使用できるかどうか
Become means its position every time
なるたびにその位置を意味します
is to be in a fixed position
一定の位置にいることです
still have to fix
まだ修正しなければならない
just its electron
その電子だけ
Its components will get smaller and smaller
そのコンポーネントはますます小さくなります
Could it be that this instrument will get better and better?
この楽器はますます良くなるのでしょうか？
Of course, the instruments are getting smaller and smaller
もちろん、楽器はどんどん小型化しています
It will be more convenient for us to do field work
現場作業がもっと便利になります
but that is to say
しかし、それはつまり
If we want to make good progress on positioning
ポジショニングをうまく進めたい場合
very precise
非常に正確な
then we wish to say
それから私たちは言いたいのです
where everything is placed
すべてが置かれている場所
That point is not moving
それが動かないポイントです
But if I measure today
でも今日測ったら
I may be a little crooked
私は少し曲がっているかもしれません
or if it is not quite right
またはそれが完全に正しくない場合
Maybe my coordinates are not so precise
私の座標はそれほど正確ではないかもしれません
That's because of the map and deformation we're looking at
それは私たちが見ているマップと変形のせいです
is very tiny
とても小さいです
That kind of error is actually very difficult
こういうミスって実はすごく難しいんです
just not allowed
ただ許可されていないだけ
right
右
so i see your picture
だからあなたの写真を見ます
You want three corners to stand over there
あそこに3つのコーナーが立って欲しいです
very fixed
非常に固定されている
It must be very stable to put something on it
上に何かを置くのは非常に安定している必要があります
Yes, just keep calm
はい、落ち着いてください
and we have that
そして私たちはそれを持っています
to that spherical position
その球状の位置へ
Then the height should be measured accurately
次に、高さを正確に測定する必要があります
And it takes a long time
そして長い時間がかかる
because from
なぜなら、から
Actually that's it
実はそれだけです
Because your car generally uses these positioning
あなたの車は通常これらの位置決めを使用するため、
Maybe a few meters error
もしかしたら数メートルの誤差かもしれない
but we sat
でも私たちは座っていました
Kilometer error
キロ誤差
So that level is much different
だからレベルが全然違うんだよ
So we rely on
だから私たちが頼りにしているのは、
Good instrument and long-term implementation
優れた機器と長期的な実装
Then there is a way to achieve
それから達成する方法があります
The progress of this positioning of the minimeter
ミニメーターの位置づけの進捗
right
右
It should be possible in the future
将来的にはできるはずだ
Because we actually have some
実際にいくつか持っているので、
cheaper receiver
安価な受信機
that is
あれは
become smaller and smaller
どんどん小さくなる
But it's small words that become words
でも小さな言葉が言葉になるんだ
You want to spread a large area
広範囲に広げたい
That is, the distance between your sides should be shortened.
つまり、両脇間の距離を縮める必要があります。
Then the observation time will be longer
そうすると観察時間が長くなります
Density is going to be higher
密度はもっと高くなります
So it's hatchback to balance
だからバランスをとるためにハッチバックなんだ
right
右
And I just said that we are laying things on the bottom of the sea
そして、私たちは海の底に物を置いていると言いました。
And because it goes through a lot of sea water on it
そして、その上でたくさんの海水を通過するため、
So it transmits this GPS signal
つまり、この GPS 信号を送信します
can't get out of this sea
この海から出られない
so you're going to use deep wave on the side
だからサイドでディープウェーブを使うことになる
to talk to it to test it
話しかけてテストする
Why is this measurement
なぜこの測定なのか
because you are near the United States
あなたはアメリカの近くにいるので
You just have a few boards down there
そこにはボードがいくつかあるだけです
It takes 24 hours to pick up this signal
この信号を受信するまでに 24 時間かかります
Because in seawater it actually
なぜなら、実際に海水中では
Because the sea itself is always moving
海自体は常に動いているから
So its own
それで、それ自体の
It's the deep wave transmission
それが深波動送信です
When it comes up, it is that the change of deep wave speed will be quite large.
それが出てくると、深波速度の変化がかなり大きくなるということです。
Because it is different from yours, such as the temperature of sea water, there will be some changes
海水温などあなたのものとは違うので多少の変化はあります
And then the walrus changes, and these are the sources of the so-called errors
そしてセイウチは変化し、これらがいわゆるエラーの原因となります
Let's just say, what if we can collect as many observations as possible?
できるだけ多くの観測値を収集できたらどうなるでしょうか?
We can try to eliminate these errors as much as possible.
これらのエラーを可能な限り排除するように努めることができます。
Because it's inside because there are a lot of internal waves in the sea
海の中は内部波が多いので内側にあるからです。
These things are difficult for you to eliminate with models
これらをモデルで排除するのは困難です
The only way is if you observe long enough
唯一の方法は、十分に長く観察することです
And then because the path between your two deep waves to that ship is similar
そして、その船までの 2 つの深い波の間の経路が似ているからです。
Then you can use the differential method to slightly eliminate these signals
次に、差動法を使用してこれらの信号をわずかに除去できます。
But if you want to achieve good observation progress
しかし、良好な観察の進歩を達成したい場合は、
Or the more observations, the better
または、観察が多ければ多いほど良い
Or you use two boats and put that cost cost
あるいは、ボートを 2 隻使用して、そのコストを投入します
This is a matter of cost and popularity
これはコストと人気の問題です
Yes because we do now, do this sea word
はい、今やるからこの海の言葉をやってください
Basically, the wind and waves are sometimes very strong
基本的に風と波が時々非常に強いです
Many people have at least half
半分以上持っている人も多い
probably not working at sea
おそらく海上では機能しないでしょう
Yes, because we do this
はい、私たちがこれを行うので、
you have work to do at sea
海でやるべき仕事がある
so you have to keep
だからあなたは守らなければなりません
is working
は働いている
no cloud boat
雲のボートはありません
first request
最初のリクエスト
ok, is there anything else
わかりました、他に何かありますか
Questions everyone wants to ask
みんなが聞きたい質問
Then I think everyone understands
それならみんなも分かると思うよ
not too many problems
あまり問題は多くない
if so
もしそうなら
we're ending the day a little early
少し早く一日を終える予定です
Thank you Dr. Xu again
徐先生、またよろしくお願いします
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
our this
私たちのこれ
great speech
素晴らしいスピーチ
I'm here to make a notice
お知らせするためにここに来ました
we next month
私たちは来月
Feast of Knowledge in November
11月の知識の饗宴
it was on november 28
それは11月28日でした
We will go to the National Taiwan University campus
国立台湾大学のキャンパスへ行きます
Lecture Hall of the Institute of Atomic and Molecular Sciences
原子分子科学研究所大講堂
we will change the subject again
また話題を変えます
It's Xu Lifen, a researcher from the life science side.
生命科学側の研究者の徐立芬です。
in the Agricultural Biotechnology Research Center of our hospital
当院農業バイオテクノロジー研究センター内
He will talk about when tradition meets modernity
彼は伝統と現代が出会うときについて話します
We are going to discuss the effects of Taiwanese herbal medicine research on cancer
台湾の漢方薬研究が癌に及ぼす影響について議論する予定です
so welcome
ようこそ
Information about this talk should be available on our website
この講演に関する情報は私たちのウェブサイトで入手できるはずです
Thank you again for coming to our feast of knowledge
知識の饗宴にご来場いただきまして誠にありがとうございます
Good night
おやすみ